好了，准备了，专心
OK Here we go。Focus.
速度，我是速度
Speed。I am speed.
1个赢家，41个输家
One winner，42 losers.
我把输家当早餐吃
I eat losers for breakfast.
早餐
Breakfast.
也许我该吃早餐，可能会比较好
Wait，maybe I should have had breakfast.
不不不不…保持专心，速度
A little breck-y could be good for me。No，no，no，stay focused。Speed.
疾如风，快如电
I'm faster than fast。Quicker than quick.
我是“闪电”！
I am lightning！
嘿， “闪电”，准备好了吗
Hey，Lightning！You ready？
没错，“闪电”早就准备好了
Oh，yeah。Lightning's ready
咔嚓！
Ka-chow！
《赛车总动员》
来买天线球喔
Get your antenna balls here！
冲啊， “闪电”！
Go，Lightnin'！
哇喔！ 你说对了，滑头
Whoo！You got that right，slick.
欢迎回到戴诺可400
Welcome back to the Dinoco 400.
我是鲍伯，跟我的好朋友达洛
I'm Bob Cutlass，here with my good friend，Darrell Cartrip.
赛车进行到一半了，今天可能是赛车史上重要日子
We're midway through what may be an historic day for racing.
鲍伯，现在我的油压暴升
Bob，my oil pressure's through the roof.
比赛要是更刺激的话，恐怕我得被拖着出去了
If this gets more exciting，they're gonna have to tow me outta the booth！
的确是的，达洛
Right，Darrell.
三部领先的车，以相同的积分
Three cars are tied for the season points lead，
进入本季最后一场比赛
heading into the final race of the season.
这场比赛的胜利者， 将赢得季冠军头衔，跟活塞奖杯
And the winner of this race will win the season title and the Piston Cup.
绰号“冠军”的史崔威勒
Does The King，Strip Weathers，
是不是能在退休以前再夺得一次胜利呢
have one more victory in him before retirement？
他是戴诺可赞助多年的金童
He's been Dinoco's golden boy for years！
能不能赢得最后一个活塞奖杯呢？
Can he win them one last Piston Cup？
还有就是一如往常的，第二名“路霸”
And，as always，in the second place spot we find Chick Hicks.
在他的赛车生涯中，始终都位居第二
He's been chasing that tailfin his entire career.
路霸以为今年是他的幸运年
Chick thought this was his year.
终于有机会脱离“冠军”史崔威勒的阴影
His chance to finally emerge from The King's shadow.
可是他万万没想到半路杀出个程咬金， “闪电”麦坤！
But the last thing he expected was Lightning McQueen！
你知道吗，我看没有人想到
You know，I don't think anybody expected this.
这位菜鸟新秀，原本是个无名小子
The rookie sensation came into the season unknown.
现在大家都认识他了
But everyone knows him now.
他会是第一个赢得活塞奖杯， 跟戴诺可赞助的菜鸟吗？
Will he be the first rookie to win a Piston Cup and land Dinoco？
赛车传奇，亚军，和菜鸟
The legend，the runner-up，and the rookie！
三部车，一个冠军！
Three cars，one champion！
哦，不，你休想！
No you don't.
呵呵！
Hey！
哦，闪电，快啊！
What a ride！
超过去，麦坤！超过去！
Go get 'em，McQueen！Go get 'em！
我爱你！ “闪电”！
I love you，Lightning！
戴诺可是我的！
Dinoco is all mine.
有状况，第三弯道！
Trouble，turn three！
冲过来啊，麦坤 不好，领先车的后面撞成了一团
Get through that，McQueen。Huge crash behind the leaders！
等一下，达洛，麦坤冲进车阵了
Wait a second，Darrell。McQueen is in the wreckage.
那个菜鸟绝对不可能过得去！
There's no way the rookie can make it through！
至少不是毫发无伤
Not in one piece，that is.
耶！
Yeah！
“闪电”！喔！
Lightning！Oh！
你看看！麦坤过去了耶！
Look at that！McQueen made it through！
天呐！ “闪电”麦坤精彩突围
A spectacular move by Lightning McQueen！
耶！咔嚓！
Yeah！Ka-chow！
麦坤！麦坤！麦坤！ 麦坤！麦坤！麦坤！
McQueen！McQueen！McQueen！McQueen！McQueen！McQueen！
耶，麦坤！咔嚓！
Yeah，McQueen！Ka-chow！
当其他赛车都进维修站的时候
While everyone heads into the pits，
麦坤继续跑，取得领先
McQueen stays out to take the lead！
别让我退出啊，教练 我还可以跑！
Don't take me out，coach。I can still race！
哈哈，你们觉得怎么样？很厉害吧
What do you think？A thing of beauty.
麦坤他不休息！ 什么？
McQueen made it！What？
他不进站！
He's not pitting！
快，快让我出站 快！快让我回去，快！
You gotta get me out there！Let's go！Get me back out there！
麦坤居然不进站维修！
McQueen's not going into the pits！
那个菜鸟刚开除了他的总机械师， 那是本季第三位了！
The rookie fired his crew chief。The third this season！
他自个儿说喜欢独立自主的 跑！跑！跑！
Says he likes working alone。Go，go！
路霸被维修给耽搁了
Looks like Chick got caught up in the pits.
对，停了那么久，他可有一大段路要追呢
Yeah，after a stop like that，he's got a lot of ground to make up.
男士们，准备好，要开始喽！
Get ready，boys，we're coming to the restart！
让开 让开 让开！
Come on，come on，come on！
我们需要轮胎！快点！快点！
We need tires now！Come on，let's go！
不不不不！不要轮胎，汽油就好 什么？
No，no，no，no！No tires，just gas！What？
你需要轮胎，你这白痴！
You need tires，you idiot！
看来麦坤今天只打算加了汽油就跑啊
Looks like it's gas-and-go's for McQueen today.
没错，还是不换轮胎
Right。No tires again.
通常我会说这就像是在炒短线
That's a short-term gain，long-term loss，
可是对他挺有效的！嘿嘿，显然他懂的比我们多啊
but it's workin' for him。He obviously knows somethin' we don't know.
决胜时刻到了，达洛，只剩一圈 闪电麦坤遥遥领先
This is it，Darrell。One lap to go and Lightning McQueen has a huge lead.
哦，他赢定了，把庆功宴准备好吧！
He's got it in the bag。Call in the dogs and put out the fire！
新的赛车王就要产生喽！
We're gonna crown us a new champion！
方格旗，我来喽！
Checkered flag，here I come！
哦，糟了！麦坤爆了一个轮胎！
No！McQueen's blown a tire！
只剩最后一个弯道，他撑得住吗？
And with only one turn to go！Can he make it？
傻瓜！
You fool！
麦坤爆胎了！麦坤爆胎了！
McQueen's blown a tire！He's blown a tire！
快快快！
Go，go，go！
他又爆了一个轮胎！
He's lost another tire！
“冠军”跟“路霸”急起直追！ 他们进入第三弯道了
King and Chick come up fast！They're entering turn three！
加油
Come on.
我真不敢相信我的眼睛！
I don't believe what I'm watching，Bob！
“闪电”麦坤距离活塞奖杯只差一百英尺！
Lightning McQueen is 100 feet from his Piston Cup！
“冠军”和“路霸”通过第四弯道
The King and Chick rounding turn four.
他们来到直线跑道了 结果是…
Down the stretch they come！And it's，and it's
实在是太接近了，根本看不出来啊 不敢相信！我真不敢相信！
It's too close to call！Too close！I don't believe it！
我们爱你， “闪电”！
Lightning！
这真是我们赛车史上最精彩，
The most spectacular，amazing I don't believe it！
最叹为观止， 最不可思议的结局啊！
unequivocally，unbelievable ending in the history of the world！
我们连谁赢了都不知道 看看！
And we don't know who won！Look at that！
太接近了，怎么看啊 可以再放一次吗？请再放一次
That's very close to call。Can we play that again？
嘿！不准照相！快走开！
Hey，no cameras！Get outta here！
我们在胜利之道等候赛车结果
We're here in Victory Lane，awaiting the results.
麦坤，不换胎是很冒险的举动哦
McQueen，that was a risky move，not taking tires.
这还用说
Tell me about it！
你会不会后悔没有总机械师
Are you sorry you didn't have a crew chief out there？
呵呵，柯琳 赛车不光是只为了赢，还有别的
Oh，Kori。There's a lot more to racing than just winning.
我是说领先一整圈赢得冠军 这样有什么看头啊
I mean，taking the race by a full lap Where's the entertainment in that？
我要给赛车迷一点刺激
I wanted to give folks a little sizzle.
剌激？ 我后不后悔没有总机械师？
Sizzle？Am I sorry I don't have a crew chief？
不，不后悔，因为我是个人秀
No，I'm not。'Cause I'm a one-man show.
什么？喔，是啊
What？Oh，yeah，right.
没错，那是非常有自信的“闪电”麦坤
That was a confident Lightning McQueen.
记者柯琳·泰伯薇在胜利之道的现场报道
Live from Victory Lane，I'm Kori Turbowitz.
嘿，别挡镜头 嘿，查理
Get outta the shot。Yo，Chuck.
你做什么啊？你挡到镜头了
Chuck，what are you doing？You're blockin' the camera！
大家都想看闪电 什么？
Everyone wants to see the bolt。What？
退后一点 嘿，够了，我们走吧
Now，back away。That's it！Come on，guys.
唉呀，你们要去哪儿啊 我们辞职，个人秀先生
Whoa，team！Where are you going？We quit，Mr。One-Man Show！
好啊，走啊
Oh，OK，leave。Fine.
呵呵，我要上哪去找能帮我加油的组员呢
How will I ever find anyone else who knows how to fill me up with gas？
再见，查理 我的名字不叫查理！
Adios，Chuck！And my name is not Chuck！
哦，随便了
Oh，whatever.
嘿，闪电！呦，麦坤！
Hey，Lightning！Yo！McQueen！
说真的，刚才的冲刺可真精彩啊
Seriously，that was some pretty darn nice racin' out there.
我是说我！
By me！Oh，yeah.
欢迎进入路霸的年代
Zinger！Welcome to the Chick era，baby！
活塞奖杯是我的，我的
The Piston Cup It's mine，dude。It's mine.
嘿，各位，我开戴诺可蓝色车怎么样？戴诺可蓝！
Hey，fellas，how do you think I'd look in Dinoco blue？Dinoco blue！
别做梦了，雷鸣
In your dreams，Thunder.
是呀，雷鸣？他在说什么？ 不知道啊
Yeah，right。Thunder？What's he talkin' about，「Thunder」？
因为雷声总是在闪电后面
You know，'cause thunder always comes after lightning.
呯！咔！
Ka-ping！Ka-pow！
你们谁知道雷声这个玩笑 我不知道
Who knew about the thunder thing？I didn't.
好个平手的结局啊，你让戴诺可很骄傲哦
That was one close finish。You sure made Dinoco proud.
谢谢你，冠军
Thank you，King.
老德啊，这些年来你对我很好
Well，Tex，you've been good to me all these years.
这是我应该做的
It's the least I could do.
不论发生什么事 你都是我心目中的赢家，老公
Whatever happens，you're a winner to me，you old daddy rabbit.
谢了，老婆 没有你我什么也不是
Thanks，dear。Wouldn't be nothing without you.
我是蜜亚 我是蒂亚
I'm Mia。I'm Tia.
我们最崇拜你了 咔嚓！
We're，like，your biggest fans！Ka-chow！
哦，做我真好
I love being me.
好了，小姐们，够了 我们爱你， “闪电”！
OK，girls，that's it。We love you，Lightning！
嘿，朋友，你真的很有胆识啊
Hey，buddy。You're one gutsy racer.
噢，冠军先生
Oh，hey，Mr。The King.
你光是一个螺丝
You got more talent in one lug nut
就比很多车子拥有更多赛车细胞
than a lot of cars has got in their whole body.
真的？这个… 但是你很笨
Really？Oh，that But you're stupid.
你说什么？ 这不是独角戏啊，孩子
Excuse me？This ain't a one-man deal，kid.
你要放聪明点 给自己找一个一流的总机师和伙伴
You need to wise up and get a good crew chief and a good team.
你想赢，一定要有好人才
You ain't gonna win unless you got good folks behind you，
在背后支持，让他们做他们的工作
and you let them do their job，like they should.
必须要每个人同心协力 一流的伙伴
Like I tell the boys at the shop A good team.
耶
Yeah
哦！ “闪电”！
Oh，Lightning！
只要你想清楚了，前途无可限量
If you figure that out you just gonna be OK.
哦，对，真的是非常好的建议
Oh，yeah，that That is spectacular advice.
谢谢，冠军先生
Thank you，Mr。The King.
各位女士先生
Ladies and gentlemen，
活塞杯赛车史上头一遭
for the first time in Piston Cup history
一位菜鸟赢得活塞奖杯
A rookie has won the Piston Cup.
耶！
Yes！
今天我们有三辆车平手
we have a three-way tie.
嘿！麦坤，你一定很尴尬吧
Hey，that must be really embarrassing.
可是我不会放在心上，因为尴尬的不是我
But I wouldn't worry about it。Because I didn't do it！
因为今天的比赛有三位平手， 所以裁判决定，一星期后
Piston Cup officials have determined that a tiebreaker race
将在加州举行三位领先者的决赛
between the three leaders will be held in California in one week.
谢谢！谢谢所有观众！谢谢！
Well，thank you！Thanks to all of you out there！Thank you！
嘿，菜鸟，谁第一个到加州， 就可以单独跟戴诺可谈
Hey，first one to California gets Dinoco all to himself.
不，不是我 你们才是最棒的
No，not me！No，you rock，and you know that！
喔耶！喔
Oh，yeah！Whoo！
好的，来吧
Yep！All right！Got it！
谁第一个到加州，就可以单独跟戴诺可谈
「First one to California gets Dinoco all to himself.」
那就看看谁会先到，路霸
Oh，we'll see who gets there first，Chick.
嗯？
Huh？
嘿！小子，恭喜你争取到决赛 我不想谈这件事
Hey，kid！Congrats on the tie。I don't want to talk about it.
好了，麦大叔，出发了 我的拖车到哪去了？
Let's go，Mack。Saddle up。What'd you do with my trailer？
我把它停在你赞助者帐篷 什么？
I parked it at your sponsor's tent。What？
你必须亲自去露个脸
Gotta make your personal appearance.
不、不、不不不不…
No。No！No，no，no，no！
对对对，我是闪电麦坤
Yes，yes，yes！Lightning McQueen here.
我用新配方“清锈”保险杆除锈药膏
And I use Rust-eze Medicated Bumper Ointment，new rear end formula！
“清锈”让生锈保险杆一擦见效
Nothing soothes a rusty bumper like Rust-eze.
哇！马上亮晶晶！
Wow！Look at that shine！
使用“清锈” 你也能像我一样帅
Use Rust-eze and you too can look like me！
咔嚓！
Ka-chow！
我遇到来自沼泽的一辆车
I met this car from Swampscott.
他锈得很严重，连影子都没有
He was so rusty he didn't even cast a shadow.
你可以看见他肮脏的底盘
You could see his dirty undercarriage.
我讨厌生锈的车，这对我形象非常不好
I hate rusty cars。This is not good for my image.
你要感谢他们的赞助 再说你签了合约
They did give you your big break。Besides，it's in your contract.
哦，别说了，好吗？ 去牵拖车就好了
Oh，will you stop，please？Just go get hooked up.
冬天是个好季节 这一点没什么好争辩的
Winter is a grand old time。Of this there are no ifs or buts.
可是要记住喔，那些盐跟灰尘
But remember，all that salt and grime
会让你的螺丝钉生锈，螺丝帽结冰
Can rust your bolts and freeze your
嘿！你们看，他来了耶
Hey，look！There he is！
冠军角逐者
Our almost champ！
快过来，小子
Get your rear end in here.
闪电麦坤，你太快了
Lightning McQueen，you are wicked fast！
那场赛车真是精彩啊 对，你好快，麦坤
That race was a pisser！You were booking！
拜托，让我过一下 你是我的偶像！
Give me a little room。You're my hero！
麦坤先生 是，我知道
Yes，I know.
弗瑞 弗瑞，谢谢
「Fred.」 Fred，thank you.
他知道我的名字！他知道我的名字！
He knows my name。He knows my name！
不错，弗瑞
Looking good，Freddie！
多亏你了，让我们今年赚了不少
Thanks to you，Lightning，we had a banner year！
很好，我们应该有足够的钱帮你买头灯喽
We might clear enough to buy you some headlights.
你是说他没有头灯？
You saying he doesn't have headlights？
我就是这么说的，那些只是贴纸
That's what I'm telling ya。They're stickers！
你们知道的 赛车不需要什么头灯
Well，you know，racecars don't need headlights，
因为跑道啊，一向都是明亮的啊
because the track is always lit.
我弟是秃头，他还是需要头灯
Yeah，well，so is my brother，but he still needs headlights.
各位女士先生 闪电麦坤
Ladies and gentlemen，Lightning McQueen！
唱歌
Free Bird！
各位知道吗？ “清锈保险杆药膏”车队
You know，the Rust-eze Medicated Bumper Ointment team
今天表现的非常好
ran a great race today.
还有，别忘了，只要一点“清锈”
And remember，with a little Rust-eze
加上大量的运气
And an insane amount of luck，
你也可以像我一样帅 咔嚓
you too，can look like me。Ka-chow.
嘿，小子 我们爱你
Hey，kid。We love ya.
而且我们期盼明年也是业绩长红
And we're looking forward to another great year.
跟今年一样！
Just like this year！
明年我就不干了
Not on your life.
别像我弟那样开车 是吗？别像我哥那样开车
Don't drive like my brother！Yeah，don't drive like my brother！
亲爱的加州，我们来了
California，here we come！
戴诺可，我们来了！
Dinoco，here we come！
好舒服喔，哪位？
Oh oh uh，I needed this。Hello？
请问是全世界最快的赛车，闪电麦坤吗？
Is this Lightning McQueen，the world's fastest racing machine？
你是最棒的经纪人哈威吗？
Is this Harv，the world's greatest agent？
当你的经纪人真荣幸啊
And it is such an honor to be your agent
我几乎不忍心拿你一成的奖金 还有广告酬劳
that it almost hurts me to take ten percent of your winnings.
永久的经纪权了 总之，好精彩的比赛
Merchandising。And ancillary rights in perpetuity。Anyway，what a race，champ！
我没…我没看 可是听说你很棒
I didn't see it，but I heard you were great.
谢了，哈威
Thanks，Harv.
听着，你有二十张加州决赛的票
Listen，they're giving you 20 tickets for the tiebreaker thing in Cali.
我可以帮你拿给你朋友，你告诉我名字
I'll pass 'em on to your friends。Shoot me the names.
让哈威为你服务，好吗？宝贝 是，朋友
You let Harv rock it for you，baby。Right。Friends.
是，有，嗯…
Yes，there's
好吧，我懂了，人气小子
OK，I get it，Mr。Popular.
朋友太多，不知道给谁好 嘿，你到城里来
So many you can't even narrow it down。Hey，when you get to town，
最好抽空来看你最好的朋友
you better make time for your best friend！
你一定要跟你的好友吃顿饭
Break bread with your mishpocheh here！
对，这样很好，我们是应该…
That'd be great！We should totally
我得挂了，小子 让我知道情况，再见
OK，I gotta jump，kid。Let me know how it goes。I'm out.
什么？小货车？
What？A minivan？
拜托，麦大叔 你开到慢车道了
Come on，you're in the slow lane.
你载的是闪电麦坤耶
This is Lightning McQueen you're hauling here.
我只要停一会就好了，小子
Just stopping off for a quick breather，kid.
绝对不可以
Old Mack needs a rest。Absolutely not.
我们要整夜赶路，一直到加州去 我们说好的
We're driving all night till we get to California。We agreed to it.
整夜？让我提醒你国家交通部规定… 拜托，麦大叔
All night？May I remind you federal DOT regs state
我要比路霸先到，跟戴诺可聊聊
Come on，I need to get there before Chick and hang with Dinoco.
那些打盹的卡车
All those sleeping trucks.
嘿，小子，我不知道我能不能做得到
Hey，kid，I don't know if I can make it.
你当然可以，麦大叔
Oh，sure you can，Mack.
很容易啊，我陪你熬夜
Look，it'll be easy。I'll stay up with you.
一整夜？ 一整夜
All night？All night long.
嘿呦，DJ 干嘛？
Hey，yo，D.J。What up？
有一辆车在打瞌睡喔
We got ourselves a nodder.
音乐真好听
Pretty music.
嘿，文哥，换车道了，老兄
Yo，Wingo！Lane change，man.
回你那边啦
Right back at ya！Yeah！
没有碰到 你在渡假吗？
Oops！I missed。You going on vacation？
哦，糟了，大鼻！ 他要打喷嚏啦！
Oh，no，Snot Rod He's gonna blow！
保重身体
Gesundheit！
绝对不要边打瞌睡边开车
One should never drive while drowsy.
麦大叔！
Mack！
嘿，麦大叔！麦大叔！
Hey，Mack！Mack！
麦大叔！
Mack！
麦大叔 等等我！
Mack，wait for me！
麦大叔！
Mack！
麦大叔！麦大叔！
Mack！Mack！
麦大叔！麦大叔…
Mack！Mack
等等！麦大叔！
wait up！Mack.
麦大叔！麦大叔！
Mack！Mack！
你不是麦大叔
What？You're not Mack.
麦大叔？我不是麦大叔 我是大卡车，拜托
Mack？I ain't no Mack！I'm a Peterbilt，for dang sake！
开你的头灯，白痴
Turn on your lights，you moron！
麦大叔…州际公路
Mack The Interstate！
在我辖区里休想超速
Not in my town，you don't.
哦，糗了
Oh，no.
哦！也许他可以帮我
Oh，maybe he can help me！
他向我开枪？ 他为什么向我开枪？
He's shooting at me！Why is he shooting at me？
我好多年没跑这么快了
I haven't gone this fast in years.
我的密封垫一定会裂开
I'm gonna blow a gasket or somethin'.
蛇行！蛇行！蛇行！
Serpentine！Serpentine，serpentine！
搞什么呀？
What in the blue blazes？
居然蛇行，飙车狂
Crazy hot-rodder.
（史丹利 我们的城镇奠基者 1909）
我告诉你，老兄 闪第三次都比较慢
I'm telling you，man，every third blink is slower.
60年代太亏待你了，是吗？
The sixties weren't good to you，were they？
什么？那不是州际公路
What？That's not the Interstate！
不不不
No，no，no，no，no，no！
不是只有我看到，对吧？
I'm not the only one seeing this，right？
危险！
Incoming！Whoa，man.
嘿！你刮了我的漆
No！Hey！
我的轮胎！
My tires！
飞走吧，史丹利，自由自在
Fly away，Stanley。Be free！
小子，你的麻烦可大了
Boy，you're in a heap of trouble.
记者正在洛杉矶国际赛车场
We're live at the Los Angeles International Speedway
第一位决赛者闪电麦坤 他来了
as the first competitor，Lightning McQueen，
刚刚到赛车场 麦坤先生，旅途顺利吗？
is arriving at the track.
他真的要上《赛车女郎》杂志吗？
Is it true he's gonna pose for Cargirl？
闪电，你的策略是什么？
What's your strategy？
怎么啦？我忘了擦挡泥板吗？
What？Did I forget to wipe my mud flaps？
（闪电麦坤失踪了！！）
麦傅脑怂统档酱锛又？但是麦坤不见了
McQueen's driver arrived in California，but McQueen was missing.
赛车“闪电麦坤”神秘失踪了 麦坤应该参加一场前所未有的…
McQueen was reported missing。to race an unprecedented
赞助厂商说不知道他在什么地方
Sponsor stated they have no idea where he is.
我只希望“闪电”没事 我实在不希望他发生任何意外
I hope Lightning's OK。I'd hate to see anything bad happen to him.
我不知道什么比较难找 闪电麦坤还是肯跟他合作的总机械师
I don't know what's harder to find，McQueen or a chief who'll work with him！
不计代价，一定要找到闪电麦坤！
Lightning McQueen must be found at all costs！
他们都在问同一个问题： 麦坤到底在哪里？
They're all asking the same question：Where is McQueen？
天啊
Oh，boy.
这是什么地方啊？
Where am I？
早啊，睡美人！
Mornin'，sleepin' beauty！Ah！
我在想你要多久才会醒过来
Boy，I was wonderin' when you was gonna wake up.
你要什么就拿去，只要别伤害我
Take whatever you want！Just don't hurt me！
轮胎锁？ 为什么给我上轮胎锁？
A parking boot？Why do I have a parking boot on？
这是怎么回事？拜托 哈哈，你真好笑
What's going on here？Please！You're funny.
我喜欢你，我叫拖线
I like you already。My name's Mater.
拖线？
Mater？
对，拖把的拖，不是脱衣服的脱
Yeah，like 「tuh-mater」，but without the 「tuh」.
你叫什么名字？ 你…你不知道我的名字？
What's your name？You don't know my name？
嗯…我知道你的名字 你也叫拖线？
No，I know your name。Is your name Mater too？
什么？
What？
听我说，我必须在最短的时间内尽快赶到加州去 这是什么地方啊？
Look，I need to get to California as fast as possible。Where am I？
这是什么地方？嘿
Where are you？Shoot！
这是化油器郡
You're in Radiator Springs.
一个可爱的小镇，叫油车水镇
The cutest little town in Carburetor County.
好，好极了
Oh，great。Just great！
如果你认为这里很好 你应该参观镇上其他的地方
Well，if you think that's great，you should see the rest of the town.
你知道吗？ 我很想参观其他的地方
You know，I'd love to see the rest of the town！
所以只要你打开门，解开轮胎锁
So if you could just open the gate，take this boot off，
你跟我就一起游览本地的风景好吗？
you and me，we go cruisin'，check out the local scene
耶，好 怎么样，拖线？
Dad-gum！How'd that be，Tuhmater？
酷！ 拖线！
Cool！Mater！
我说过，你可不可以跟被告说话？
What did I tell you about talkin' to the accused？
不可以
To not to.
那就废话少说 把这个威胁道路的罪犯，拖去交通法庭
Well，quit your yappin' and tow this delinquent road hazard to traffic court.
等会聊了，小老弟
Well，we'll talk later，Mater.
小老弟，真好笑
「Later，Mater.」 That's funny！
油车水镇交通法庭即将开庭
The Radiator Springs Traffic Court will come to order！
你刮了我的漆 真该放把火把你烧了
Hey，you scratched my paint！I oughta take a blowtorch to you，man！
我得重新叠罐头 你弄坏道路，你是辆坏车
You broke-a the road！You a very bad car！
暴君！ 对啊，对啊
Fascist！Commie！
警长，请告诉我，这到底还要多久？
Officer，talk to me，babe。How long is this gonna take？
我很忙，得立刻赶到加州去
I gotta get to California，pronto.
你的律师呢？
Where's your lawyer？
谁知道，在大溪地吧 他在那里有一个度假屋
I don't know。Tahiti maybe。He's got a timeshare there.
当被告没有律师的时候 法庭会指派一个给他
When a defendant has no lawyer，the court will assign one to him。Hey！
谁要当他的律师啊？
Anyone want to be his lawyer？
对，我可以，警长
Shoot，I'll do it，Sheriff！
请起立，法官大人韩大夫主审
All rise！The Honorable Doc Hudson presiding.
爱现
Show-off.
希望韩大夫怜悯你这个可怜虫
May Doc have mercy on your soul.
好了，
All right，
我要知道谁破坏我的镇 警长
I wanna know who's responsible for wreckin' my town，Sheriff.
我要拿下他的车盖
I want his hood on a platter！
我要他坐牢，直到他烂掉 不，更正
I'm gonna put him in jail till he rots！No，check that.
我要他坐牢，直到监牢烂掉，压在他车顶
I'm gonna put him in jail till the jail rots on top of him，
然后再把他移到新的坚牢，让那个监牢也烂掉
and then I'm gonna move him to a new jail and let that jail rot.
我…
I'm
把他撵出去，警长
Throw him out of here，Sheriff.
我要他离开我的法庭 我要他离开我的镇
I want him out of my courtroom。I want him out of our town！
本案终结 好耶
Case dismissed。Yes！
我可是一流的律师耶
Boy，I'm purty good at this lawyerin' stuff.
抱歉，我迟到了
Sorry I'm late，Your Honor！
保时捷美眉，她一定是我的律师派来的
Holy Porsche！She's gotta be from my attorney's office.
谢谢你来，不过没事了
Hey，thanks for comin'，but we're all set.
他要放我走 他要放你走？
He's letting me go。He's letting you go？
对，今天你的工作很轻松
Yeah，your job's pretty easy today.
你只需要乖乖站在那儿 让我好好的看看你
All you have to do now is stand there and let me look at you.
好吧，我就不拐弯抹角了， 我…你…晚餐，咔嚓
Listen，I'm gonna cut to the chase。Me，you，dinner。Pi-cha-kow！
什么？噢！哦 咔嚓！
What the？Ow！Oh！Ka-chow！
拜托！哦 我知道，这种反应我见多了
Please！I know。I get that reaction a lot.
我带给别人的感受 连他们自己都无法理解
I create feelings in others that they themselves don't understand.
对不起，吓着你了吗？
Oh，I'm sorry。Did I scare you？
嗯…有一点，但我不要紧
A little bit，but I'll be all right.
好吧，我要去跟法官谈谈
OK。I'm gonna go talk to the judge.
做你该做的，宝贝 喔！但是小心一点
Do what you gotta do，baby。But listen。Be careful.
这里的人不是都像你一样那么上路 你懂我的意思吗？
Folks around here are not firing on all cylinders，if you know what I mean.
咔嚓！
Ka-ching！
我会记住的
I'll keep that in mind.
你好，拖线 你好，莎莉
Hey there，Mater。Howdy，Sally.
大家好 早安，莎莉
Hi，folks！Good morning！
你认识她？
You know her？
她是本镇的律师，也是我的未婚妻
She's the town attorney and my fiancee.
什么？
What？
开玩笑的 她只是喜欢我的外表
Nah，I'm just kiddin'。She just likes me for my body.
韩大夫，你今天看起来真帅 你是不是调整了你的侧视镜？
You look great。You do something different with your side view mirrors？
莎莉，你想做什么？
What do you want，Sally？
哦，拜托，让这个家伙修路 本镇很需要
Come on，make this guy fix the road。The town needs this.
不，我知道他这型的，赛车
No。I know his type。Racecar.
本镇最不需要赛车
That's the last thing this town needs.
好吧，我不想这么做的喔 可是你让我别无选择
OK，I didn't want to have to do this，Doc，but you leave me no choice.
各位乡亲，你们都知道本镇的骄傲历史
Fellow citizens，you're all aware of our town's proud history.
她又来了
Here she goes again.
油车水镇，原始道路
Radiator Springs，the glorious jewel
也是我们66号公路颈上的一颗荣耀宝石
strung on the necklace of Route 66，the mother road！
我们有责任也很乐意 服务行经这段公路的所有旅客
It is our job and our pleasure to take care of the travelers
旅客？什么旅客？
on our stretch of that road。Travelers？What travelers？
别理他
Ignore him.
可是你们仔细想想 如果没有路让这些旅客行驶
But how，I ask you，are we to care for those travelers
那我们要怎么服务他们呢？
if there is no road for them to drive on？
卡布，你的店里有什么？ 轮胎
Luigi，what do you have at your store？Tires.
如果没有车子来呢？
And if no one can get to you？
我就没办法卖轮胎，我会失去一切
I won't sell any tires。I will lose everything！
芙蓉，你的店里有什么？ 我有汽油
Flo，what do you have at your store？I have gas.
很多汽油 好了，男士们，注意听
Lotsa gas！OK boys，stay with me.
芙蓉，如果车子不能去 你的店里买汽油会怎么样呢？
And，Flo，what'll happen if no one can come to your station to buy gas？
我会没生意，然后… 我们就得离开这里
I'll go outta business and we'll have to leave town.
如果芙蓉关了她的店离开这里 我们会怎么样呢
What's gonna happen if Flo leaves town and closes her station？
没有汽油，我们就完了 什么？
Without gas，we're done for！What？
所以你们不觉得那辆车 有责任帮我们修路吗？
Don't you think the car responsible should fix our road？
我看啊，唯一壮得可以修那道路的是大艾尔
The only guy strong enough to fix that road is Big Al！
莉丝，那家伙十五年前就离开了
Lizzie，Big Al left like，15 years ago.
那么你干吗提起他呀，糊涂虫
Then why are you bringing him up，you lemon？
哦，他可以修
Oh，he can do it.
他有足够的马力，所以你们要他做什么啊？
He's got the horsepower。So，what do you want him to do？
修马路！
Fix the road！
因为我们的镇需要修复 耶！
Because we are a town worth fixing！Yeah！
大家肃静
Order in the court！
这件事似乎由不得我了
Seems like my mind has been changed for me.
耶！ 不！
Yeah！No！
我刚刚不应该邀请你去吃晚餐的
Oh，I am so not taking you to dinner.
没关系，贴纸王，你可以请贝西
That's OK，Stickers。You can take Bessie.
哦，天啊，你可以跟贝西工作
Man，you get to work with Bessie！
那真是一个求之不得的机会
I'd give my left two lug nuts for somethin' like that.
贝西？谁是贝西？
Bessie？Who's Bessie？
（贝西）
她就是贝西 有史以来最好的一台铺路机
This here is Bessie，finest road-pavin' machine ever built.
我现在判决你做社区服务
I'm hereby sentencing you to community service.
你要在我的监督下修复那条马路
You're gonna fix the road under my supervision.
什么？这地方疯了？
What？This place is crazy！
嘿，我知道现在时机可能不对
I know this may be a bad time right now，
可是你欠我三万两千块的律师费哦
but you owe me $32，000 in legal fees.
什么？
What？
所以我要把你跟贝西接在一起 你要轻轻拉她
We're gonna hitch you up to Bessie，and you're gonna pull her nice.
你一定是在开玩笑
You gotta be kidding me.
你从路的起点那儿开始
You start there where the road begins.
一直铺到路的尽头那儿结束
You finish down there where the road ends.
我的妈呀
Holy shoot！
这…这…这要多久的时间啊？
Whoa，whoa，whoa！How long is this gonna take？
这个啊…做对的话，应该只要五天左右
Well，fella does it right，should take him about five days.
五天？
Five days？
可是我现在就应该在加州跟戴诺可见面
But I should be in California schmoozing Dinoco right now！
那么你最好少说废话，开始工作
Then if I were you，I'd quit yappin' and start workin'！
接起来吧，拖线 好的，遵命
Hook him up，Mater。Okay-dokey.
翘头喽！
Freedom！
也许我该…嗯…先把他勾住贝西
Maybe I should've hooked him up to Bessie
再嗯…再拿掉轮胎锁
and then then took the boot off.
（这么快就要走了？）
再见，油车水 再见，贝西
Goodbye，Radiator Springs，and goodbye，Bessie！
加州，我来了！
California，here I come！Yeah！
嗯，迎着风
Oh，feel that wind.
太好了
Yes！
不不不…没油了
No，no，no，no，no。Outta gas？
我怎么可能会没油呢？
How can I be outta gas？
小子啊，我们没你想像那么笨啊
Boy，we ain't as dumb as you think we are.
可…可是…你们怎么…
But how did，how did you？
我们趁你昏迷抽了你的汽油
We siphoned your gas while you were passed out.
咔嚓
Ka-chow。Ow，ow，ow，ow.
男士们 警长
Gentlemen。Sheriff.
嗨！警长
Hey，Sheriff.
轮胎怎么在这儿？
Why here？Sono sempre stati qui.
它们在原来的地方比较好
They were better before。Stai sempre a parlare.
奇诺 小红，让开一下
Guido！Red，can you move over？
我要看那部性感的改装车
I want to get a look at that sexy hot rod.
你知道吗？我以前很会吹口哨
You know，I used to be a purty good whistler.
当然现在不行了
I can't do it now，of course，on account of sometimes
因为有时候我的引擎本体里会有液体累积
I get fluid built up in my engine block，
可是韩大夫说他会修理 他几乎什么都能修
but Doc said he's gonna fix it。He can fix about anything.
所以我们才让他当法官
That's why we made him the judge.
小子啊，你真该听我唱“跟着我马车跑”
Boy，you shoulda heard me on Giddy-up，Oom Papa Mow Mow.
人们大老远
Now，I'm not one to brag
就是要来听我唱这个“跑”
but people come purty far to see me get low on the 「Mow-Mow」.
哦！天啊！这下可好了！ 怎么了
Aw，man，that's just great！Hey，what's wrong？
我的幸运贴纸都被弄脏了
My lucky sticker's all dirty.
啊，那没什么，我帮你弄干净
Ah，that ain't nothin'。I'll clean it for ya.
不不不…
No，no，no！
算了，没这个必要
That won't be necessary.
喂！喂！大块头 对，你红色的
Hey！Hey，big fella！Yeah，you in the red！
我需要水管 把我身上的脏东西冲掉
I could use a little hose down。Help me wash this off.
他要去哪？
Where's he goin'？
他只是有点害羞 而且他恨你弄死他的花
Oh，he's a little bit shy，and he hates you for killin' his flowers.
我不该忍受这些的
I shouldn't put up with this.
我是速度和空气力学的精密仪器
I'm a precision instrument of speed and aerodynamics.
你伤到哪啦？ 我是很有名的赛车！
You hurt your what？I'm a very famous racecar！
你是很有名的赛车？真正的赛车？
You are a famous racecar？A real racecar？
是，我是真正的赛车 你以为呢？看看我
Yes，I'm a real racecar。What do you think？Look at me.
我一辈子都在注意赛车消息 一辈子
I have followed racing my entire life。My whole life！
那你一定认识我，我是闪电麦坤
Then you know who I am。I'm Lightning McQueen.
闪电麦坤 对！对！
Lightning McQueen？Yes！Yes！
我要向全世界呐喊
I must scream it to the world！
我的兴奋到了无以复加的最高点
My excitement from the top of someplace very high！
你认识很多法拉利吗？ 不是，不是，不是
Do you know many Ferraris？No，no，no，no，no.
他们是跑欧洲巡回赛 我是跑活塞杯
They race on the European circuit。I'm in the Piston Cup！
怎么了？ 卡布只注意法拉利跑车
What？Luigi follow only the Ferraris.
天啊，我有没有看错啊？
Is that what I think it is？
顾客上门了
Customers.
顾客上门了，各位 有顾客
Customers！Customers，everyone！Customers！
好了，大家冷静点 顾客上门了
OK！Customers？
我们等很久了，记住我们排练过的
Been a long time。Remember what we rehearsed.
快拿出“营业中，欢迎光临”的牌子
Make sure your 「Open，please come in」 signs are out.
你们知道该怎么做 好了，大家别慌，准备好
You all know what to do。All right，nobody panics。Here we go！
志明，奇怪，我没看到任何匝道啊
Van，I just don't see any on-ramp anywhere.
春娇，我很清楚我们在什么地方 是吗？我们在荒郊野外
Minny，I know exactly where we are。Yeah，we're in the middle of nowhere.
老婆，拜托 两位好
Honey，please。Hello.
欢迎光临饰品谷的入口 油车水镇
Welcome to Radiator Springs，gateway to Ornament Valley.
我们以优质服务和热诚好客闻名
Legendary for its service and hospitality.
很高兴为您服务
How can we help you？
我们什么也不需要，谢谢你 亲爱的，问她怎么去州际公路
We don't need anything，thank you。Ask for directions to the Interstate.
我们没有必要问路，春娇 我告诉过你，我知道该往哪里走，我…
There's no need to ask for directions。I know where we're going.
上回我们去谢科琵市的时候，他也是这样
He did the same thing on our trip to Shakopee.
我们是去参加狂欢节庆典，可是我们…
We were headed over there for the Crazy Days，and we
好了，好了 真的，我们不需要服务
OK。Really。We're just peachy，OK？What you really need
你们真正需要的是我自制美味的有机燃料
is the sweet taste of my homemade，organic fuel.
不， 我的油箱无法消化
No，it doesn't agree with my tank.
我们只想找到州际公路 很高兴见到你，士兵
Just trying to find the Interstate。Good to see you，soldier！
请到“士官长军品店”买你们需要的政府军用品
Come on by Sarge's Surplus Hut for your government surplus needs.
老公，军用品 我们有很多军用品了
Honey，surplus！We have too much surplus.
我的交通锥汽车旅馆那儿有张地图
I do have a map over at the Cozy Cone Motel.
而且你们住宿的话 我们还供应好吃的免费早餐
And if you stay，we offer a free Lincoln Continental breakfast.
老公，她有地图 我不需要地图，我有GPS
Honey，she's got a map。I don't need a map！I have the GPS.
再也不需要地图，谢谢 要不要喝点什么？
Never need a map again，thank you。How 'bout somethin' to drink？
请到我的“芙蓉咖啡” 66号公路上的最佳燃料
Stop at Flo's V-Eight Cafe。Finest fuel on Route 66.
不，我们刚加过油
No we just topped off.
如果你们需要轮胎 请到在下卡布的轮胎店
And if you need tires，stop by Luigi's Casa Della Tires，
店名叫“比萨斜塔”
home of the Leaning Tower of Tires.
我们只想找到州际公路 可是你们一定需要烤漆
We're trying to find the Interstate。But you do need a paint job.
雷蒙帮你们烤得美美的 嘿，什么图案都行
Ramone will paint you up right。Hey，anything you want！
像是火焰图案.不 谢谢
You know，like a flame job。No thanks
或是幽灵火焰图案
Maybe ghost flames！
你们喜欢传统的细条纹？ 肯尼霍华风格，是吗？
You like old school pinstripin'？Von Dutch style？
哦！老公，你看，细条纹
Oh，honey，look。Von Dutch.
嗯，不必了，我们要走了，好吗？
OK，no。We're gonna be going now，OK？
一个小小的纪念品，嗯？
A little somethin' to remember us by，OK？
好 有空再来，好吗？
OK！Come back soon，OK？
你们知道我们在哪 告诉你的朋友喔
I mean，you know where we are！Tell your friends！
（绮丽孤峰 油车水镇）
好，是，当然了
OK！Yes。You bet.
非常谢谢你们，再见喽！
Thanks again，folks。Bye-bye now.
嘿…
Psst！Psst！Hey！Hey，hey，hey！
我知道怎么去州际公路 哦？真的？
I know how to get to the Interstate！Do ya？
春娇，不要 真的、真的、真的、真的
Minny，no。Yeah，yeah，yeah.
不，不是真的，可是听着…
No，not really。But listen.
我是著名的赛车闪电麦坤 我被强押在这里
I'm Lightning McQueen，famous racecar。I'm being held against my will.
我要拜托你们通知我的伙伴 让他们来救我
I need you to call my team，so they can come rescue me
好让我及时赶去加州，赢得活塞杯 你们懂吗？
and get me to California in time for me to win the Piston Cup。Understand？
不不不…
No，no，no，no，no，no，no.
别走，这是真的，拜托你们 你们一定得帮我，别把我丢在这儿
No，it's the truth！I'm telling you！You gotta help me！Don't leave me here！
我在蛮荒地带，我的智商正一秒一秒下降
I'm in hillbilly hell！My IQ's dropping by the second！
我快变得跟他们一样了喽
I'm becoming one of them！
好了，别担心，他们知道我们的位置了
OK，don't worry。They know where we are now.
他会告诉他们的朋友，等着瞧
They'll tell friends。You'll see.
我们马上回到汉克威廉斯
We'll be back for our Hank Williams marathon
很好 现在我们先听听活塞杯最新消息
That's good。after a Piston Cup update.
还是没有闪电麦坤的踪影 在这同时路霸已经抵达加州
Still no sign of Lightning McQueen。Chick arrived in California
成为今天第一位在跑道上练习的赛车
and today became the first car to spend practice time on the track.
是啊，很高兴能比其他对手先练习
It's nice to get out here before the other competitors.
因为抢得先机，对我有利
You know，get a head start。Gives me an edge.
嘿嘿！麦坤，气死你
Hey，McQueen Eat your heart out.
拖线，让我搞清楚
Let me get this straight.
路铺好了，我就可以走 是这样的，对吧？
I can go when this road is done。That's the deal，right？
他们都是这么说的啊 好吧，别挡住我
That's what they done did said。OK。Outta my way.
我要铺好这条路
I got a road to finish.
完成了 完成？
He's done！Done？
才一个钟头
Uh-huh。It's only been an hour.
我做好了，看，我完成了
Ah，I'm done。Look，I'm finished.
只要说一声谢谢，我就走 只要一声谢谢
Say thanks，and I'll be on my way。That's all you gotta say.
我是第一个踏上新马路的
Whee-hoo！I'm the first one on the new road！
挺平顺的
It rides purty smooth.
简直糟透了 但是跟这个镇很相配
It looks awful！Well，it matches the rest of the town.
小红
Red.
你以为你是谁啊
Who do you think you are？
听着，韩大夫说 我做好了就可以走，条件是这样
Look，Doc said when I finish，I could go。That was the deal.
条件是你把路修好，不是弄得更糟
The deal was you fix the road，not make it worse.
快把它刮掉，重新开始
Now，scrape it off！Start over again.
嘿！拜托，老爹 我不是推土机，我是赛车
Hey，look，grandpa，I'm not a bulldozer。I'm a racecar.
哦…是吗？ 那么我们来比一场怎么样啊？我和你
Is that right？Then why don't we just have a little race？Me and you.
什么？ 你和我，这是玩笑吗？
What？Me and you。That a joke？
你赢了，你走，我来修路
If you win，you go and I fix the road.
我赢了，你照我的方式修路
If I win，you do the road my way.
韩大夫，你在做什么呀
Doc，what're you doin'？
不要怪我没礼貌，韩大夫
I don't mean to be rude here，
可是你从零到一百公里要多久？ 三年半够吗？
but you probably go zero to sixty in，like，what？Three-point-five years？
那么你应该没有什么好担心的了
Then I reckon you ain't got nothin' to worry about.
你知道吗？老古板 这是一个很好的主意，就比吧
You know what，old-timer？That's a wonderful idea。Let's race.
两位，这场比赛只跑一圈
Gentlemen，this will be a one-lap race.
你们跑到威利岗，绕过威利岗，然后回来
You will drive to Willy's Butte，go around Willy's Butte and come back.
不准碰撞，不准作弊
There will be no bumpin'，no cheatin'，no spittin'，
不准吐口水，不准咬 不准施暴，不准伤害
no bitin'，no road rage，no maimin'，
准洒油，不准推，不准挤 不准暗伤，不准霸占道路，
no oil slickin'，no pushin'，no shovin'，no backstabbin'，no road-hoggin'，
还有不准闲逛
and no lollygaggin'.
速度，我是速度
Speed。I'm speed.
有凯迪拉克的优雅，有BMW的劲爆
Float like a Cadillac，sting like a Beemer.
我的朋友奇诺 一直希望能帮真正的赛车维修
My friend Guido，he dream to give a real racecar a pit stop.
我们比赛只有一圈，两位
The race is only one lap，guys.
只有一圈，不需要维修
Uno lappo！Don't need any help.
我是个人秀 好，随你便
I work solo mio。Fine。Race your way.
不需要维修，你懂吗？ 好吧
No pit stoppo。Comprendo？OK.
两位
Gentlemen
发动你们的…引擎
start your engines！
天啊，你们看！
Hijole！Check that out！Whoa.
好主意，韩大夫 这下甭想把路修好了
Great idea，Doc。Now the road will never get done.
卡布
Luigi？
各就各位，预备
On your mark，get set
一是为了钱，二是为表演
Uno for the money，due for the show，
三是准备好，四是… 我真不敢相信，跑！
tre to get ready，and quattro to I can't believe it。Go！
韩大夫，旗子代表跑
Doc the flag means go.
记得旗子？可以跑了，跑
Remember the fl Here we go。Go.
嗯，韩大夫，你在做什么啊？
Doc，what are you doing，man？
哦，天啊，我好像一开始就落后了
Oh，dear。It would seem I'm off to a poor start.
晚一点总比不动好 走吧，拖线
Well，better late than never。Come on，Mater.
可能需要一点帮忙 呃…好吧
Might need a little help。Uh OK.
你带了绳索了？
You got your tow cable？
是啊，我一向都带着绳索，怎么了？
Well，yeah，I always got my tow cable。Why？
待会就知道了
Oh，just in case.
不不不…
No，no，no，no，no！
我的天啊！
Oh，man！Whoa.
嘿！这一招有凯迪拉克的优雅吗？ 还是有BMW的劲爆啊？
Hey！Was that floatin' like a Cadillac or was that stingin' like a Beemer？
我糊涂了
I'm confused.
你开车跟你修路一样
You drive like you fix roads.
差劲！钓上来吧，拖线
Lousy！Have fun fishin'，Mater.
我觉得他好像知道你会出事哦
I'm startin' to think he knowed you was gonna crash！
谢谢你，拖线，谢了
Thank you，Mater。Thank you.
我可以在泥土上转弯的
I can make a little turn on dirt.
不是吗？
You think？
不，现在我落后了一天 我永远别想离开这里
No。And now I'm a day behind。I'm never gonna get outta here！
嘿！你需要新烤漆，朋友
Hey，ese！You need a new paint job，man！
不用，谢了 要不要有机燃料啊？
No，thank you。How 'bout some organic fuel？
那个畸形玩意？ 不用了
That freak juice？Pass.
看他工作让我都渴了，还有谁要喝饮料的啊？
Whoo！Watchin' him is makin' me thirsty。Anybody else want somethin' to drink？
我不要，芙蓉
Nah，not me，Flo.
我正在实施特殊饮食法
I'm on one of them there special diets.
我现在是速度和空气力学的精密仪器
I'm a precisional instrument of speed and aero-matics.
你开车跟你修路一样
「You race like you fix roads.」
等着瞧，你等着瞧
I'll show him。I will show him！
可恶！我恨死了
Oh，great！I hate it！
音乐，蛮悦耳的
Hate，hate，hate，hate it！Music。Sweet music.
也许这个主意还不错
Maybe this wasn't such a good idea.
油车水镇，快乐的地方
Radiator Springs，a happy place！
好，贝西，你觉得这样好笑？
OK，Bessie，you think that's funny？
好极了！我居然跟贝西说话 我跟贝茜说话
Great！I'm talking to Bessie now！I'm talking to Bessie！
哇哦！
Wow.
早安，莎莉
Mornin'，Sally！
嘿，你看闪电麦坤 刚铺好的这条漂亮的新马路
Hey，look at this here fancy new road that Lightnin' McQueen done just made！
是啊，好漂亮哦！
Yes！Uh，amazing！
哦…雷蒙，我好久没看到你这么贴地
Oh，Ramone！Mama ain't seen you that low in years.
我好久没看到这么样的马路
I haven't seen a road like this in years.
那么溜达溜达吧，宝贝 街头漫步
Well，then let's cruise，baby。Low and slow.
哦！好美，太美了
E bellissima！It's beautiful！
奇诺，你看 就像天使铺的一样
Guido，look，it's-a like it was paved by angels.
小子，我告诉你
Boy，I tell you what.
我敢说天上的路都没这么平
I bet even the roads on the moon ain't this smooth.
韩大夫，你看看
Doc，look at this！
我们啊，早就该把他丢进仙人掌堆里了
Shoulda tossed him into the cactus a lot sooner，huh？
他还没完成呢，还有很长一段路
Well，he ain't finished yet。Still got a long way to go.
奇诺，你看卡布
Guido，look at Luigi！
这实在太棒了
This is fantastico！
看起来好好玩哦 拖线，我先预约，下一个是我
That looks like fun！Mater，I got dibs，next turn！
嘿，卡布，新马路让你的店 看起来像垃圾场
Hey，Luigi，this new road makes your place look like a dump.
那女人嘴巴真毒
That crazy old devil woman.
她说的对！
She's right！
奇诺
Ah！Guido！
那小子居然做得不错
Huh。That punk actually did a good job.
嗯，慢着，他跑哪去了？
Well，now where the heck is he？
警长，他是不是又跑掉了
Sheriff！Is he makin' another run for it？
不不，他半夜里啊 柏油用完了
No，no。He ran outta asphalt in the middle of the night，
问我他可不可以到这个地方来
and asked me if he could come down here.
他只想把那个弯给搞定
All he's tryin' to do is make that there turn.
不不不…啊…可恶
No，no，no，no！Oh，great.
我在每个赛车场上过弯都无懈可击
Perfect turns on every track I've ever raced on.
怎么会栽在那个弯上？ 警长，我看你去芙蓉那儿加点油吧
Sheriff，why don't you go get yourself a quart of oil at Flo's.
我来看着他
I'll keep an eye on him.
谢了，大夫 我也觉得我的油快没了
Well，thanks，Doc。I've been feelin' a quart low.
这不是柏油路，孩子，这是土
This ain't asphalt，son。This is dirt.
拜托，你来做什么？幸灾乐祸？
Oh，great。What do you want？You here to gloat？
你没有三轮刹车，所以你得提前快转
You don't have three-wheel brakes，so you got to pitch it hard，
甩尾，然后用油门操控
break it loose and then just drive it with the throttle.
速度太快的话，你会冲出道路的
Give it too much，you'll be outta the dirt and into the tulips.
你是法官、医生， 还是个赛车专家
So you're a judge，a doctor and a racing expert.
简单的说
I'll put it simple.
当你向左急转的话，会发现自己滑向右边
If you're goin' hard enough left，you'll find yourself turnin' right.
哦！对，很有道理 前轮往右左转，是啊，谢谢
Oh Right。That makes perfect sense。Turn right to go left！Yes！Thank you！
或者我该说“不谢”
Or should I say，「No，thank you」？
因为按照你的逻辑 不谢的意思就是谢谢
Because in Opposite World，maybe that really means，「Thank you」！
什么古董老爷车，真是白痴
Crazy grandpa car。What an idiot！
前轮往右左转
Turn right to go left.
救命！
Ow！
前轮往右左转，你猜怎么样？我试了
Turn right to go left。Guess what。I tried it.
结果你知道吗？ 发生了怪事，我往右转
You know what？This crazy thing happened I went right！
你再继续跟自己说话，大家会以为你疯了
You keep talkin' to yourself，people'll think you're crazy.
谢谢你的忠告 什么？我不是跟你说话
Thanks for the tip。What？I wasn't talkin' to you！
哦！奇诺，好漂亮 什么？
Oh，Guido，e bellissimo！Che cosa？
我是说好漂亮 哦…你喜欢啊
It looks great！This is great！Ti piace，eh？Si，si，bellissimo.
哦！天啊！
Oh，Lord.
拖线！
Mater！
今天晚上你看守囚犯
I need you to watch the prisoner tonight.
怎么又是我 等一下，万一他又想逃跑呢？
Well，dad-gum！Wait a minute。What if he tries to run again？
那就让他把油耗光，再把他拖回来
Just let him run outta gas and tow him on back.
可是要盯着他 遵命
But keep an eye on him。Yes，sir！
我被困在这儿铺这条差劲的路
While I'm stuck here paving this stinkin' road，
“路霸”却在加州跟戴诺可打屁
Chick's in California schmoozing Dinoco.
我的戴诺可，哦，谁碰我？
My Dinoco。Whoa，whoa，whoa！Who's touching me？
你的轮胎漏气，奇诺会修
You have a slow leak。Guido，he fix.
你把马路铺得很好
You make-a such a nice new road.
你到我店里来 卡布好好照料你
You come to my shop。Luigi take-a good care of you.
虽然你不是法拉利
Even though you not a Ferrari.
你买四个轮胎 我送你一个备胎
You buy four tires，I give you a full-a size spare
完全免费！ 卡布，我所有的轮胎都是免费的
absolutely free！Look，I get all my tires for free.
我喜欢你的风格
I like your style，eh？
你很会杀价，好吧 卡布再给一次机会
You drive the hard bargain。OK。Luigi make you a new deal.
你买一个轮胎 我送你三个不用钱
You buy one tire，I give you three for free！
哦，你瞧瞧
Oh，would you look at that？
雷蒙，雷蒙
Ramone，Ramone！
那么卡布再给你一次机会
Then Luigi make you a new new deal.
不不不… 不必了，不用，谢谢
No，no，no，no。Deal me out。Pass。No，thank you.
不不不 这可是最后一次机会了
No，no，no，no。No。This is it。My last offer.
你买一个轮胎 我免费送你七个雪地轮胎！
You buy one tire，I give you seven-a snow tires for free！
有兴趣来找我，你知道我在哪里
Done。You interested，you call me。You know where I am.
不！停！不要！
Stop！Let me
小红，你漏了一个地方 就在那儿
Oh，Red，you missed a spot。See it right there？
那…那…那车盖那儿 不
No！No！On the hood right there.
好冷
Stop，stop！That's cold！
救命
Help！Please！Stop！
谢了，小红
Thanks，Red.
这是做什么啊
What was that for？
你要不要住三角锥啊 啊？
Do you want to stay at the Cozy Cone？Huh？
你要住就得干干净净的
If you do，you gotta be clean.
别看这蛮荒地带，还是有一定水准的
'Cause even in hillbilly hell we have standards.
什么？我…我不懂 没什么
What，I？I don't get it.
我只是想说… 谢谢你把路铺得这么好
I thought I'd say thank you for doin' a great job.
所以我想让你跟我住 不是跟我住
So I thought I'd let you stay with me。I mean，not with me！
是住那儿，不是跟我住那儿 是你住你自己的三角锥
But there。Not with me there，but there in your own cozy cone.
我住我的三角锥，就在… 慢点，慢点，你是在对我示好
And I'd be in my cone，and it's Wait。Wait，you're being nice to me.
如果你想留在肮脏的拖吊场 随你便
If you want to stay at the dirty impound，fine.
我了解你们这种罪犯类型 不不不…没关系
I understand you criminal types。No，no，no，no。That's OK.
好，三角锥 它才重新整修过
Yeah，the Cozy Cone。It's newly refurbished.
是啊，有趣的笑话
Yeah，it's like a clever little twist.
旅馆房间是三角锥 通常车辆应该要避免的
The motel's made out of caution cones，which，of course，cars try to avoid.
可是现在却给我们住，真好玩
But now we're gonna stay in them。That's funny.
什么都瞒不过你，是吗？
Figure that all out on your own，did you？
要的话，住一号
Cone number one，if you want.
嘿，我是不是看到你后面有细纹刺青？
Hey，do I spy a little pinstriping tattoo back there？
哦，那只是…哦！
Oh That's just a Oh！
啊！你看见了？我要走了
Oh，you saw that？Yeah。Just gonna be going.
我要…对，我走喽
Gonna Yeah.
你知道吗？ 我以前认识一个女孩朵玲
You know，I knew this girl Doreen.
很漂亮的女孩
Good-lookin' girl.
看起来就像跑车，不过她是卡车
Looked just like a Jaguar，only she was a truck！
以前我常故意撞她，找机会跟她说话
You know，I used to crash into her，just so I could spoke to her.
拖线，你在说什么啊？ 不知道
What are you talking about？I don't know.
嘿，我知道我们今天晚上，可以做什么 因为我负责看守你
Hey，I know somethin' we can do tonight，'cause I'm in charge of watchin' you！
不，我得先铺完这条路 然后我就要离开这里
No，Mater，I gotta finish this road，and I have to get out of here.
没关系，你这个过弯失败先生
Well，that's all right，Mr。I Can't Turn On Dirt.
反正这件事情你可能做不来
You probably couldn't handle it anyway.
喂！慢着，客气点，拖线
Whoa，whoa，easy now，Mater.
你知道你在跟谁说话？ 我是闪电麦坤
You know who you're talkin' to？This is Lightning McQueen.
我无所不能
I can handle anything.
拖线，我不要做这种事 哦！走嘛，你一定会喜欢的
I'm not doin' this。Come on。You'll love it！
看牵引机出糗 这实在是太可笑了
Tractor-tippin's fun。This is ridiculous.
好了，听着
All right，listen.
我说走就走 别让牛大叔抓到你，走！
When I say go，we go。But don't let Frank catch you。Go！
哦！谁？谁是牛大叔？
Whoa！Wait！Who's Frank？
拖线！
Mater！
等一下，拖线！
Wait，Mater！
好，我教你怎么做
OK，here's what you do.
你偷偷溜到他们前面，然后叭
You just sneak up in front of 'em，and then honk.
接下来就看他们了，看着
And they do the rest。Watch this.
我发誓，牵引机太笨了
I swear，tractors is so dumb！
我告诉你，小老弟 没有比这个更爽的了
I tell you what，buddy，it don't get much better than this.
对，你活在天堂里，拖线
Yep，you're livin' the dream，Mater boy.
不管你是谁，那个就是好笑
I don't care who you are，that's funny right there.
该你了，老弟
Oh，your turn，bud.
拖线，我不能 我连喇叭都没有
Mater，I can't。I don't even have a horn.
胆小鬼 我不是胆小鬼
Baby。I'm not a baby.
好，停，停 好了，我想办法
Fine。Stop！Stop，OK？All right。I'll do something.
牛大叔
That's Frank.
跑！跑！
Run！
他来了！小心！
Here he comes，look out！
跑！他要追上你了！
Run！He's gonna get ya！
顾客
Oh！Customers！
不不不
Ah，no，no，no.
明天我们可以去找鬼火
Tomorrow night we can go look for the ghostlight！
我等不及了，拖线 是啊，小老弟
I can't wait，Mater。Oh，yeah，I'm tellin' ya！
哦，天啊！你得承认那真的好好玩
Oh，boy，you gotta admit that was fun！
哦…是啊，是啊
Oh，yeah yeah.
好了，我最好还是带你回拖吊场
Well，we better get you back to the impound lot.
你知道吗？ 莎莉要让我住汽车旅馆
You know，actually，Sally's gonna let me stay at the motel.
哦…去那里谈情说爱，是吧？ 哦，不，不…爱说笑
Oh
再说她受不了我 老实说，我也不喜欢她
Besides，she can't stand me。And I don't like her，to be honest.
对，大概是吧 嘿，你看，莎莉小姐
Yeah，you probably right。Hey，look，there's Miss Sally！
在哪？在哪？
Where，where？
你爱上莎莉小姐了 不，我没有
You're in love with Miss Sally。No，I'm not.
有，你有 没有
Yes，you do。No way.
有 听我说
Way。Come on，look
你爱上了莎莉 拜托，真幼稚
You're in love with Miss Sally！Real mature.
拖线，成熟点吧
You're in love！Real grown up.
你爱她，你爱她 等一下
You love her。You love her。Wait
你爱她！你爱她，爱她！ 好吧，好…
You love her！You love her。You love her.
拖线，拖线，够了
All right。OK。Mater，enough！
别这样好吗？ 别怎样？
Will you stop that？Stop what？
你这样倒着开，让我紧张 你会撞到什么的
Driving backwards。It's creeping me out。You're gonna wreck.
撞到？我可是全世界的倒车冠军
Wreck？Shoot！I'm the world's best backwards driver！
你注意看好了，情圣
You just watch this right here，lover boy。Wee-hee！
你在做什么？小心、小心
What are you doing？Watch out！Look out！
拖线、拖线
Mater？Mater！
拖线
Mater！
嘿！冷静一点，拖线
Hey，take it easy，Mater！
他疯了
He's nuts.
我不必看路就可以走得很稳
No need to watch where I'm goin'.
怎么样？还不赖吧？
Just need to know where I've been.
哇！你实在帅呆了 你怎么做的？
Whoa，that was incredible！How'd you do that？
全靠我的后视镜 我帮你装，还可以教你怎么用
Rearview mirrors。We'll get you some，and I'll teach you if you want.
对，也许我赛车时用得着
Yeah，maybe I'll use it in my big race.
你能不能告诉我这场赛车为什么对你那么重要？
What's so important about this race of yours，anyway？
这不是普通赛车 我们说的是活塞杯赛车
It's not just a race。We're talking about the Piston Cup！
它也是我梦寐以求的赛车
I've been dreaming about it my whole life！
我将会是历史上第一个赢得 活塞杯的菜鸟
I'll be the first rookie in history ever to win it.
到时候我就会有很多新的赞助厂商
And when I do，we're talkin' big new sponsor，
专用的直升机
with private helicopters.
不必再代言保险杆药膏 不必理会生锈的旧车
No more medicated bumper ointment。No more rusty old cars.
生锈的旧车哪里不好？
What's wrong with rusty old cars？
哦！我不是说你 我是说别的旧车，你知道吗？
Well，I don't mean you，Mater。I mean other old cars。You know？
不是你，我喜欢你 没关系，朋友
Not like you。I like you。It's OK，buddy.
喂…你认为有一天 我也可以搭乘那种直升机吗？
Hey，you think maybe one day I can get a ride in one of them helicopters？
我是说我一直梦想 能够搭乘那种豪华的直升机
I mean，I've always wanted to ride in one of them fancy helicopters.
可以，可以，当然可以 真的吗？
Yeah，yeah，yeah，sure，sure。You mean it？
当然，你要什么都行
Oh，yeah。Anything you say.
我就知道 我就知道我没有选错
I knew it。I knowed I made a good choice！
选什么？
In what？
最好的朋友
My best friend.
明早见了，小老弟
See you tomorrow，buddy！
麦坤和莎莉躲在树底下
McQueen and Sally parked beneath a tree，
两部车子在玩亲亲
Ki-s-somethin'-somethin'-somethin'-t！
一号、一号、一号
Number one。Number one Ah，number one！
哇！挺不错的 嘿！贴纸王
Ah，this is nice。Hey，Stickers.
抱歉 你吓了我一跳
I'm sorry。You scared me。You gotta be careful.
你要小心点 我被你被我吓一跳吓一跳
I scared myself scaring you scaring me.
我其实不是真的吓到 不，当然不是，不…
I mean，I wasn't like scared scared。No，of course not。No.
我只是…只是… 只是我听到你跟拖线的谈话
I was more I overheard you talkin' to Mater.
什么时候？刚…刚才吗？ 你…你听到什么？
When？Just now？What，what did，what did you hear？
哦！是关于搭直升机兜风
Something about a helicopter ride.
哦！对…对 他很喜欢这点子，是吗？
Oh，yeah。Yeah，he got a kick out of that，didn't he？
你说真的？ 什么？
Did you mean it？What？
让他坐直升机 哦…谁知道？
That you'll get him a ride。Who knows？
我总得先离开这个地方参加赛车
First things first。I gotta get outta here and make the race.
你知道，拖线他信任你
You know Mater trusts you.
哦，好吧
Yeah，OK.
这什么意思？ 什么？
Did you mean that？What？
你的意思是“哦！好吧” 还是“哦！好吧”，或是“嗯…好吧”
Was it just a 「Yeah，OK」，or 「Yeah OK」 or 「Yeah，o-OK」？
拜托，我累了，今天实在是有一点忙
Look，I'm exhausted。It's kinda been a long day.
哦！好吧，晚安
Yeah，OK。G'night.
喂…谢谢
Hey，thank you.
你刚说什么？
What did you just say？
谢谢你让我住在这里
You know，thanks for lettin' me stay here.
很高兴能离开拖吊场 而且这里…很棒
It's nice to be out of the impound，and this is It's great.
刚整修过，是吗？ 是
Newly refurbished，right？Yeah.
晚安 晚安
G'night。Good night.
拜托你关掉那个破音乐 好不好
Will you turn that disrespectful junk off？
这是吉他教父罕醉克斯经典作
Respect the classics，man。It's Hendrix！
不！
No！
我一定得离开这儿
I gotta get outta here！
嘿，你有没有看到警长 哦，我的天
Hey，have you seen the Sheriff？Oh！Oh，my gosh.
嘿，你做什么？ 看得过瘾吗，都市小子？
Hey，what are you doin'？Get a good peek，city boy？
我…我只是需要警长给我今天的汽油配给
I just need my daily gas ration from the Sheriff.
去芙蓉那儿等他，你快走吧
Wait for him at Flo's。Get outta here.
我三天前就想离开这里了
I've been trying to get outta here for three days！
希望你大饱眼福了
Hope you enjoyed the show！
韩大夫
Whoa，Doc.
你该整理一下车库了 老哥，拜托
Time to clean out the garage，buddy，come on.
什么？
What？
他有活塞奖杯？
He has a Piston Cup？
我的天啊
Oh，my gosh.
三座活塞奖杯
Three Piston Cups？
牌子是写着禁止入内
Sign says stay out.
你有三座活塞奖杯，你怎么会有…
You have three Piston Cups。How could you have
我只知道你不会开车 没想到你也不识字
I knew you couldn't drive。I didn't know you couldn't read.
你是韩森黄蜂！ 我不是说过了吗？到芙蓉那儿去等
You're the Hudson Hornet！Wait at Flo's，like I told ya！
对了，我以前居然没有想到
Of course。I can't believe I didn't see it before.
你是出神入化的韩森黄蜂！
You're The Fabulous Hudson Hornet！
你曾经是单季最多胜利的纪录保持人
You used to hold the record for most wins in a season。Oh，we gotta talk.
哦，你要教我，教我你的技巧，拜托 我已经试过了
You gotta show me your tricks。Please。I tried that.
我是说你三次拿到冠军 看看那些奖杯
You won three times！Look at those trophies！
你看，我只看见一堆空杯子
You look。All I see is a bunch of empty cups.
你知道吗？做做汽车瑜伽 可以增加你的马力跟扭力
You know，some automotive yoga could really lower your RPM's，man.
哦，好了，去洗车吧，嬉皮
Oh，take a car wash，hippie.
嘿！快看看我老公 呼！真亮眼
Yeah，look at my husband，y'all！Whoo！That's your color！
黄色，宝贝 你帅呆了
Yellow，baby。Mmm。You smokin' hot！
他来了
There he is.
哦，我的天！各位！ 你们知道韩大夫是有名的赛车吗？
Oh，my gosh！Did you know Doc is a famous racecar？
韩大夫？我们的韩大夫？ 不是可能
Doc？Our Doc？Not Doc Hudson.
不不不，我说的是真的！ 他是真正赛车界传奇
No，no，no，no，it's true！He's a real racing legend.
他是出神入化的韩森黄蜂
He's The Fabulous Hudson Hornet！
出神入化？ 我没见过他开车超过30公里
Fabulous？I never seen Doc drive more than 20 miles an hour.
难道你看过他赛车吗？
I mean，have you ever seen him race？
没有，要是有就好，听说他非常行
No，but I wish I could have。They say he was amazing！
他拿了三座活塞奖杯 他拿杯子做什么？
He won three Piston Cups！He did what in his cup？
我看这小子大概热昏头了
I think the heat's startin' to get to the boy！
可不是吗？看他好红哦
Well，I'll say！Look how red he is.
他需要上一层新的防锈涂料
I think he needs a new coat of poly，man.
你病了吗？小老弟 你的气色是有点苍白
Are you sick，buddy？You are lookin' peaked.
对，他铁定需要啊！
He needs a new coat of poly for sure！
嘿嘿！你在干什么？ 没关系，警长，你可以信任我，对吧？
Hey！What are you doin'？It's OK。You can trust me，right？
我是相信你，可是我担心是他
I trust you，all right。It's him I'm worried about.
我信任他
Hmm I trust him.
我们去兜风 兜风？
Come on，let's take a drive。A drive？
对，兜风
Yeah，a drive.
难道你们大都市的赛车从来不兜风的吗？
Don't you big city racecars ever just take a drive？
对，我们不兜风
Ah No。No，we don't.
嘿，贴纸王，你来不来啊？
Hey，Stickers！You comin' or what？
你还以为他会逃跑 嘿！你相信吗？
And you thought he was gonna run。Hey，can you believe it，man？
他居然以为韩大夫是有名的赛车
He actually thought Doc was a famous racecar！
太好笑了！
That's so too much！
好吧，你把我弄出来了 我们要去哪？
OK，you got me out here。Where are we goin'？
我不知道
I don't know.
哇…这是什么地方啊？
Wow。What is this place？
轮井
Wheel Well.
曾经是原始公路上最受欢迎的一站
Used to be the most popular stop on the mother road.
这里？
This place？
对，想想看
Yeah，imagine.
想想看当时住在这里的情形
Oh，imagine what it must have been like to stay here.
我真搞不懂你
You know，I don't get you.
保时捷怎么会沦落到这个地方？
How does a Porsche wind up in a place like this？
原因其实很简单，以前
Well，it's really pretty simple。I was
我是洛杉矶的律师 过着纸醉金迷的生活
an attorney in LA livin' life in the fast lane，and
哦！真的是这样吗？你很有钱吗？
Oh，you were，were you？Were you rich？
什么？ 我只是想弄清楚
What？Just clues to the puzzle.
嗯，好吧，那是我生活的方式
Yeah，OK。Well，that was my life.
可是你知道吗？
And you know what？
我总觉得…不快乐
It never felt happy.
是啊，我是说…真的？
Yeah。I mean really？
真的，所以我离开加州
Yeah。So I left California.
一直向前走，最后就在这儿抛锚
Just drove and drove and finally broke down right here.
韩大夫把我修好，芙蓉收容我
Doc fixed me up，Flo took me in.
是大家收容我，我就没有再离开
Well，they all did。And I never left.
是，你知道吗？我了解
Yeah。You know，I understand.
你需要休息一下，让电池充充电
You need a little R and R。Recharge the old batteries.
可是过了一阵子以后，你为什么不回去？
But you know，after a while，why didn't you go back？
我恋爱了
I fell in love.
哦 对
Oh。Yep.
是名车？ 不是
Corvette？No.
我爱上了…这个地方
I fell in love with this.
哇！好美啊
Whoa。Look at that.
你看，他们就这样开过去
Look，they're drivin' right by.
根本不知道自己错过什么
They don't even know what they're missing！
以前不是这样的
Well，it didn't used to be that way.
是吗？
Oh，yeah？
是啊，40年前，下面的州际公路并不存在
Yeah。Forty years ago，that Interstate down there didn't exist.
真的？
Really？
是，那个时候
Yeah。Back then，
车辆走的是完全不同的路
cars came across the country a whole different way.
什么意思？
How do you mean？
那时候的路，没有像州际公路这样穿过土地
The road didn't cut through the land like that Interstate.
它顺着地形走，有起，有伏，有弯曲
It moved with the land，you know？It rose，it fell，it curved.
早！ 早，天气真好
Mornin'！Nice day，huh？
车辆行驶在那条路上，不是为了节省时间
Cars didn't drive on it to make great time.
他们是在享受时光
They drove on it to have a great time.
后来呢？
Well，what happened？
公路避开我们的镇，只为了节省十分钟车程
The town got bypassed just to save ten minutes of driving.
要是能看到这里过去的盛况就好了
How great would it have been to see this place in its heyday！
啊，这样的梦，我不知道做过多少次了
Oh，I can't tell you how many times I've dreamed of that.
总有一天，我们一定会想办法 让它恢复繁荣
But one of these days we'll find a way to get it back on the map.
是啊，谢谢你带我来兜风
Yeah。Hey，listen，thanks for the drive.
真的很开心
I had a great time.
偶尔轻松一下其实挺好的
It's kinda nice to slow down every once in a while.
不客气
You're welcome.
嘿，听着，听着
Hey，listen，listen！
有人问起的话 我们是去砸信箱的，好吗？
If anybody asks you，we was out smashin' mailboxes，OK？
什么？
Wha what？
真是，油漆还没干…
Oh，man，the paint's still wet！
不不不…别进店里去
No，no，no，no！Get out of the store！
嘿，别吃我的轮胎，给你吃雪地轮胎
Hey！Don't eat the radial！Here，take-a the snow tires.
拖线 我没有去吓牵引机
Mater！I wasn't tractor-tippin'！
那么这些要命的牵引机是从哪来的？
Then where did all these gol-durn tractors come from？
快停下来 嘿！各位
Whoa，boy！Hey！Hey，guys！
有一部往这边喽
There's one goin' this way.
我去追
I got it.
过来，小牵引机，过来
Come here，little tractor，come here.
对，这才乖
Yeah，that's a good tractor.
不不不…过来
No，no，no，no，come here.
你在做什么？
What are you doing？
你不应该脱队，独自乱跑
You're not supposed to go wandering off all alone.
你换上旧赛车胎做什么？
What are you doin' with those old racin' tires？
快啊，韩大夫，开车
Come on，Doc，drive.
你真厉害
You're amazing！
你做什么？
What are you doin'？
韩大夫，等等
Doc，wait！
动作快，慢郎中
Giddup right in there！Come on，Rusty.
韩大夫，等等 说真的，你的技术出神入化
Doc，hold it！Seriously，your driving's incredible！
好极了，你可以走了 嘿，我说真的，你宝刀未老
Wonderful。Now，go away。Hey，I mean it。You've still got it！
我说你可以走了 拜托
I'm askin' you to leave。Come on.
我是赛车 你是很老的赛车
I'm a racecar，you're a much older racecar，
可是在车盖底下，我们是一样的
but under the hood you and I are the same.
我们不一样！你懂了吗？ 你给我走吧！
We are not the same！Understand？Now，get out.
像你这样的车 怎么会在高峰时期放弃呢？
How could a car like you quit at the top of your game？
你以为我放弃？
You think I quit？
（大车祸！ 韩森黄蜂 退出赛季）
对
Right.
你在1954年发生意外
Your big wreck in '54.
他们放弃我
They quit on me.
当我终于维修好 我以为会受到欢迎
When I finally got put together，I went back expecting a big welcome.
你知道他们怎么说？ 你过时了
You know what they said？「You're history.」
就转而注意旁边的菜鸟
Moved right on to the next rookie standing in line.
我仍有雄心壮志
There was a lot left in me.
却没有机会表现了
I never got a chance to show 'em.
我留着那个提醒自己再也不回去
I keep that to remind me never to go back.
我只是没有想到那个世界会…
I just never expected that that world would
会在这儿找到我
would find me here.
可是韩大夫，我不是他们 是吗？
Hey，look，Doc，I'm not them。Oh，yeah？
我不是
No，I'm not.
你除了在乎你自己什么时候关心过别人？
When is the last time you cared about something except yourself，hot rod？
你只要说出一次，我就收回我的话
You name me one time and I will take it all back.
我想也是
Uh-huh。I didn't think so.
这里的居民都很善良 彼此关怀照顾
These are good folk around here，who care about one another.
我不希望他们依赖不值得依赖的人
I don't want 'em depending on someone they can't count on.
你是说你？你在这儿多久了
Oh，like you？You've been here how long
你的朋友连你是谁都不知道
and your friends don't even know who you are？
是谁只关心自己啊？
Who's caring about only himself？
铺完那条路，你就可以走了
Just finish that road and get outta here！
拜托你，关掉那个破音乐
Will you turn that disrespectful junk off？
尊重点，这是经典音乐
Respect the classics，man.
他完成了
He's done.
他一定是趁我们睡觉的时候完成的
He must've finished it while we was all sleepin'.
一路顺风了
Good riddance.
他走了？
He's gone？
是啊！ 我们也不希望他错过那场赛车
Well，we wouldn't want him to miss that race of his.
哦！警长，你在哭吗？ 哪有啊？我很高兴
Oh，dude，are you crying？No！I'm happy！
我白天不必再分分秒秒地盯着他了
I don't have to watch him every second of the day anymore！
我很高兴他走了
I'm glad he's gone！
小红怎么了？
What's wrong with Red？
哦！他是难过你离开这里 去参加你的重要比赛
Oh，he's just sad 'cause you left town
好拿到你梦想了一辈子的活塞奖杯
and went to your big race to win the Piston Cup
得到你说过的大厂商赞助
that you've always dreamed about your whole life
还有漂亮的直升机
and get that big ol' sponsor and that fancy helicopter you was talkin' about.
呃…你没有走！
Wait a minute！
我就知道你不会不说一声就走
I knowed you wouldn't leave without saying goodbye.
你在这做什么啊？你会错过比赛
What are you doin' here？You're gonna miss your race.
别担心，我用警车护送你 我们会赶上的
Don't worry。I'll give you a police escort，and we'll make up time.
谢谢你，警长
Thank you，Sheriff.
可是你知道我不能走
But you know I can't go just yet.
为什么？
Well，why not？
我不确定这些轮胎…
I'm not sure these tires
可以送我一路到加州 维修？
can get me to California。Peet stop？
对，有谁知道卡布几点营业？
Yeah，does anybody know what time Luigi's opens？
我真不敢相信啊！四个新轮胎！
I can't a believe it！Four new tires！
闪电先生，谢谢
Grazie，Mr。Lightning。Grazie！
真没想到！ 我们多年来的第一个顾客！
Would you look at that！Our first customer in years！
我充满了狂喜的泪水
I am filled with tears of ecstasy，
因为这是我一生中最光荣的一天
for this is the most glorious day of my life！
好了，好了，卡布 给我你店里最好的黑色轮胎
All right，Luigi，give me the best set of blackwalls you've got.
不不不
No！No，no，no.
你不知道自己要什么 卡布知道你要什么
You don't-a know what you want。Luigi know what you want.
黑色的轮胎会和路面分不清楚
Blackwall tires。They blend into the pavement.
可是这些
But-a this
白色轮胎
Whitewall tires！
它们说“看着我，我在这儿，爱我”
They say，「Look at me！Here I am！Love me.」
好吧，你是专家
All right，you're the expert.
别忘了…备胎
Don't forget the spare.
好极了，奇诺
Perfetto。Guido！Peet stop！
卡布说得没错吧？
What did Luigi tell you，eh？
哇…你说得对，比法拉利还棒
Wow，you were right。Better than a Ferrari，huh？
没有
Eh No.
哇！这有机燃料真棒，为什么以前没听说过
Wow！This organic fuel is great！Why haven't I heard about it before？
这是个阴谋，朋友
It's a conspiracy，man！
石油公司控制了政府
The oil companies got a grip on the government！
他们都在骗我们耶，朋友
They're feedin' us a bunch of lies，man.
好吧，我要一箱
OK，I'll take a case.
咔嚓
Ka-chow.
她来了！ 好了，大家，各就各位，快点
Here she comes！Places，everybody。Hurry！
自然一点
Act natural.
嗨！莎莉
Hi，Sally。Buon giorno！
说吧，怎么回事啊？
All right，what's goin' on？
各位女士先生
Ladies and gentlecars，
请欢迎全新的闪电麦坤！
please welcome the new Lightning McQueen！
你觉得怎么样？
Pow！What do you think？
油车水让我焕然一新
Radiator Springs looks pretty good on me.
可不是吗
I'll say.
咔嚓
Ka-chow.
你一定可以马上融入加州
You're gonna fit right in in California.
我的天！你帮助了本镇所有的居民
My goodness。It looks like you've helped everybody in town.
只有一个除外
Yeah，everybody except one.
嘿，是不是已经很晚了？ 什么？他说什么啊？
Hey，is it getting dark out？What？What'd he say？
让我再说一次，是不是已经很晚了？
Let me say that again。Is it getting dark out？
很晚了，我们应该做什么呢？
Now，what was I supposed to do after that？
他们修了霓虹灯
They fixed their neon！
街头漫步 对，没错，宝贝
Low and slow？Oh，yeah，baby！
重现往日光彩，对吧？
Just like in its heyday，right？
比我想像的还美，谢谢
It's even better than I pictured it。Thank you.
一起兜风
Shall we cruise？
谢谢你，我很乐意
Oh，thank you，dear。I'd love to！
不不不！ 莉丝
No，no，no。Lizzie！
我还记得我老伴第一次邀我跟他一起兜风
I remember when Stanley first asked me to take a drive with him.
嘿，莎莉小姐，我可以跟你兜风吗？
Hey，Miss Sally。May I have this cruise？
可以，拖线
Of course，Mater。Uh-uh-uh！
他又问我一次，我说不行 他又再问我一次，我还是说不行 救我…
and again and I said，「No.」 He asked me again，and I said，「No.」
可是啊，他是二汽缸引擎的老顽固了
But，oh，he was a persistent little bugger for a two-cylinder.
我终于说…好吧，只兜一会儿哦
Finally I said，「All right，one little drive.」
嘿！ 谢了，拖线
Hey！Thanks，Mater.
两位，晚安了
Good evenin'，you two.
啊老伴，真希望你能看到这一切
Oh，Stanley，I wish you could see this.
我有没有看错啊？ 我不知道，芙蓉
Is that what I think it is？Oh，I don't know，Flo.
我还没有机会确认 可是我一定会问个清楚的
I haven't had a chance to find out。But I am going to find out。Hello.
不是啦，是那个
Not that。That.
有顾客？
Customers？Customers？
顾客上门了，很多顾客
Customers，everybody！And a lot of 'em！
你们知道怎么做 就像我们排练的那样
You know what to do。Just like we rehearsed.
那些是鬼火！
It's the ghostlight！
我们找到麦坤了 我们找到麦坤了！
We have found McQueen。We have found McQueen！
在哪里，在哪里 麦坤，看这边
McQueen，over here！
等一下，借过 你进了勒戒所是真的吗？
Wait，excuse me。Is it true you've been in rehab？
你是不是得了忧郁症，麦坤 对不起，什么？
Did you have a nervous breakdown？What？
麦坤装了白色轮胎 你的轮胎是不是提早报销了？
McQueen's wearing whitewalls！Your tires balding？
贴纸王！麦坤！
Stickers！
闪电麦坤被你们监禁了吗？ 去！
Was McQueen your prisoner？Shoot，no！
我们是最好的朋友 不是我自夸
We're best buds！I ain't braggin' or nothin'，
我负责在他万一逃跑的时候缉捕他
but I was in charge of huntin' him down if he tried to escape.
莎莉！莎莉！
Sally！Sally！
麦坤，你还会参加活塞杯赛车吗？
Will you still race for the Piston Cup？
贴纸王？ 莎莉！
Stickers？Sally！
给我们闪电！ 贴纸王
Come on，give us some bolt！
你在这里！感谢制造商，你还活着
You're here！Thank the manufacturer！You're alive！
麦大叔？ 你在这里，我真不敢相信！
Mack？You're here！I can't believe it！
你真是让我担心死了
You are a sight for sore headlights！
抱歉把你弄丢了，老板 我会补偿你
I'm so sorry I lost you，boss。I'll make it up to you！
麦大叔，我真不敢相信你来了
Mack，I，I can't believe you're here.
那是全世界最快的赛车吗？
Is that the world's fastest racing machine？
是哈威吗？ 是啊，他在后面
Is that Harv？Yeah。He's in the back.
给我们闪电，麦坤！ 退后，你们这些哈油的寄生虫
Show us the bolt！Get back，you oil-thirsty parasites！
老嘿，以前那个麦坤呢？ 其实我这一面比较上相
Where's the old McQueen？Actually，this is my good side here.
哈威 为我们闪电！
Harv！Harv！Give us the bolt！
哈威？ 闪电呢？麦坤
Harv？Come on！
小子，我在这儿 你好吗，哈威
Kid，I'm over here！How you doin'，buddy？
我最大的客户从地球上消失了！
My star client disappears off the face of the earth！
你说我好不好 哈威，我可以解释
How do you think I'm doing？I can explain.
我好极了！你无所不在，宝贝 收音机，电视，报纸
I'm doing great！You're everywhere！Radio，TV，the papers！
这种宣传是买不到的，你还需要我做什么？
You can't buy this kind of publicity！What do you need me for？
哦，对了，那只是一个比喻 我们有合约的
That's just a figure of speech，by the way。You signed a contract.
你在哪里？连我的GPS都找不到你
Where are you？I can't even find you on my GPS.
我在一个小镇，叫油车水
I'm in this little town called Radiator Springs.
你知道66号公路？它还在耶！ 是，很好，小子
You know Route 66？It's still here！Yeah，that's great，kid.
游戏时间结束了
Playtime is over，pal.
正当全世界都在找你的时候 戴诺可没有赞助对象
While the world's been trying to find you Dinoco has had no one to woo.
他们只好赞助谁？ 路霸！
Who are they gonna woo？Chick！
答对了 事实上你看看电视正在播什么
Bingo。In fact，check out what's on the plasma right now.
让我们看闪电！ 要看闪电？
Show us the thunder！You want thunder？
要看闪电 喀其卡、喀其卡、喀其卡
You want thunder？Ka-chicka，ka-chicka！
嘿，那是我的词！ 你一定要立刻去加州！
Hey，that's my bit！You've gotta get to Cali，pronto！
现在就给我离开油车水 不然戴诺可就免谈了，听到没有？
Just get out of Radiation Stinks now，or Dinoco is history，you hear me？
再等我一下，哈威
Just give me a second here，Harv.
不不不，等一下 嘿！你要去哪里啊？
No，wait。Where are you goin'？
回拖车上，宝贝 小子，你要更大的拖车吗？
Get in the trailer，baby。Kid！You want a bigger trailer？
莎莉，我…我要你知…
Sally，I I want you to
我希望
Look，I wish
谢谢，谢谢你所做的
Thank you。Thanks for everything.
不过是一条路 不，不只是一条路
It was just a road。No。It was much more than that.
嘿，小子，我们得走了 哈威已经气炸了
Hey，kid！We gotta go。Harv's goin' crazy！
你要是不马上上车，他就要开除我
He's gonna have me fired if I don't get you in the truck right now！
麦大叔，再等一下 你该走了
Mack，just hold it for You should go.
我知道，可是 祝你一切顺利
I know，but Good luck in California.
希望你找到你的梦想
I hope you find what you're looking for.
闪一下！ 莎莉
McQueen，come on！Sally
莎莉！ 嘿！闪电，闪闪看
Sally！Show us the bolt，McQueen！The bolt！
闪电，闪电，快点闪啊，麦坤
Hey，Lightning，show us the bolt！
快点，小子，快上车
Come on，get in the trailer。Where's the old McQueen？
就是这样，好极了，走吧
The bolt！That's it。That's right，let's go！
你是闪亮的明星 你是超级明星
You're a big shining star。You're a superstar.
反正那里也不适合你
You don't belong there，anyway.
我…等…
Whoa Wait Whoa，whoa，wait，wait！
嘿！你们看，麦坤上车要离开了
Hey，guys！McQueen's leavin' in the truck！
嘿！你是韩大夫吗？
Hey，are you Doc Hudson？
是啊 谢谢你通知我们
Yeah。Thanks for the call.
你通知他们？ 这样对大家都好，莎莉
You called them？It's best for everyone，Sally.
是对大家好还是对你？
Best for everyone or best for you？
我居然没有跟他说再见
I didn't get to say goodbye to him.
各位赛车迷 欢迎各位到场观看
Hello，race fans。Welcome to what has become，quite simply，
赛车史上最轰动的一场比赛
the biggest event in the history of racing.
活塞杯的三强鼎立赛
A three-way battle for the Piston Cup！
鲍勃，洛杉矶国际赛车场这里
There's a crowd of nearly 200，000 cars
涌进了将近20万辆车到场观赛
here at the Los Angeles International Speedway.
入场券比限量供应的收藏品还要抢手呢！
Tickets to this race are hotter than a black leather seat on a hot summer day！
“冠军” “路霸”和“闪电”麦坤
The King，Chick Hicks and Lightning McQueen
即将角逐200圈，三抢一的冠军赛
in a 200 lap，winner-takes-all，tiebreaker race.
鲍勃，你知道我见过不少世面 可是我告诉你，老弟
I got a lotta miles on me，but let me tell you somethin'.
没想到我会看见这样的比赛 实在太刺激了
I never thought I'd see anything like this。This is exciting！
事实上，几乎全国都休息一天
In fact，the country has almost shut down
就为了看许多专家口中的世纪赛车
to watch what many experts are calling 「the race of the century.」
嘿！冠军，祝你比赛顺利
Hey，King！Good luck in your last race.
你一直是我崇拜的偶像 谢了，小子，谢谢你
You've sure been an inspiration to me。Thanks，Junior。Appreciate it.
嘿，答应我，小心一点，好吗？ 遵命
Hey，be careful out there，OK？Yeah，man.
是吗？
He's hot！
你要知道结果我就告诉你吧
Wanna know the forecast？I'll give you the forecast.
我百分之百夺冠！ 太好了
A 100 percent chance of thunder！Ka-chicka！Ka-chicka！
跟我说一遍，喀其喀其喀其咔
Say it with me！Ka-chicka！Ka-chicka！
嘿！你！没有车库通行证不准进去
Hey，you！No admittance without a garage pass.
哦，没关系，闪电麦坤认识我
Oh，it's OK。Lightning McQueen knows me！
马克，今天是赛车的好日子，是不是？
Hey，Marco，it's a beautiful day for a race，isn't it？
一点也没错，安德瑞提先生 你早啊，佛瑞
Absolutely，Mr。Andretti。And good morning to you，Fred.
赛车英雄安德瑞提知道我的名字！ 你非让我进去不可了
Mario Andretti knows my name！You gotta let me in now！
抱歉了，朋友
Sorry，pal.
好，开始了，专注，速度
OK，here we go。Focus。Speed.
我是速度
I am speed.
胜利
Victory.
一位赢家，两位输家
One winner，two losers.
速度 速度 速度 速度
Speed。Speed。Speed。Speed
嘿，闪电，准备好了吗？
Lightnin'！You ready？
是是是，我…我准备好了
Yeah，yeah，yeah！I'm ready.
麦大叔，谢谢你今天担任我的维修组
Mack，thanks for being my pit crew today.
不必客气，小子，这是我该做的
Don't worry about it，kid。It's the least I could do.
毕竟我的绰号叫汽油桶
After all，「Gas Can」 is my middle name.
是吗？ 哈…骗你的
It is？Ah Not really.
尼尔森，推近 16号机，准备
Nelson！Zoom in。Ready，16？Take 16.
他来了，闪电麦坤
And there he is，Lightning McQueen！
失踪一个星期 然后在名不见经传的地方被发现
Missing all week，and then he turns up in the middle of nowhere！
那个小镇叫做油车水
In a little town called Radiator Springs.
而且还装上白色轮胎
Wearin' whitewall tires，of all things.
喀其卡、喀其卡、喀其卡
Oh！Ka-chicka！Ka-chicka！Ka-chicka！
嘿，你去哪了？麦坤 让我有点孤单
Hey，where you been？I've been kinda lonely.
没有任何同伴，除了戴诺可的车
Nobody to hang out with。I mean，except the Dinoco folks.
啊，双胞胎 你知道双胞胎以前是你的粉丝
And the twins。Of course。The ones that used to be your fans，
现在是我的红粉 总之，听听她们怎么说
but now they're my fans。Listen to what the twins think
冲！
Agh！Shoot！
各位，开始赛车吧！
Boogity，boogity，boogity，boys！Let's go racin'！
加油，你做得到
Come on，you can do it！
加油，冠军，让我们以你为荣
Come on，King，make us proud，boy！
跑了50圈，目前冠军还是稍稍领先
Fifty laps down，and The King is still holding a slim lead.
嘿，麦坤追上来了，他想从内侧超车
McQueen's got a run on him！He's lookin' to the inside！
哦！路霸给他吃了闭门羹
Oh！Chick slammed the door on him！
今天路霸可对他一点都不客气
Chick's not making it easy on him today.
可惜他今天状况不太好
He lost momentum，
现在他得重新追上去
and now he's gonna have to chase him back down！
哦！麦坤在内场打转
McQueen spins out in the infield！
只剩下我跟老家伙了
Just me and the old man，fellas.
麦坤今天逊呆了
McQueen just doesn't have it today.
嘿，小子，你还好吗？ 我不知道，麦大叔
Hey，kid，are you all right？I don't know，Mack.
我…我觉得不…
I don't think I
我大老远跑来不是要看你放弃的
I didn't come all this way to see you quit.
韩大夫？
Doc？
嘿！小老弟，加油，我们来了 天啊！你们来了！我真不敢相信！
Guys，you're here！I can't believe this！
我知道你需要总机械师 但没想到会这么糟
I knew you needed a crew chief，but I didn't know it was this bad.
你不是说永远不回来
You said you'd never come back.
我实在没选择啊，拖线没跟你说再见
Well，I really didn't have a choice。Mater didn't get to say goodbye.
再见！好了，我可以了
Goodbye！OK，I'm good.
如果你开车像修马路一样好
All right，if you can drive as good as you can fix a road
那么你闭着眼睛就能跑赢这场比赛
then you can win this race with your eyes shut.
回跑道去吧！
Now，get back out there！
大鼻，我们有事要做了 奇诺、卡布
Hot snot，we are back in business！Guido！Luigi！
你们是和专业维修员竞争
You're goin' up against professional pit crews.
动作要快 让他们连怎么输的都不知道！
You're gonna have to be fast。They will not know what bit them！
小子，你可以打败他们
Kid，you can beat these guys.
找到适合的节奏，追回落后的一圈
Find a groove that works for you and get that lap back.
你看，那个？哇…对，是他！
Is it？Oh，wow。That's him！
那是韩森黄蜂！ 鲍勃、达洛，韩森黄蜂回来了！
Is that？That's the Hudson Hornet！The Hudson Hornet's back！
达洛，麦坤给自己找到了维修组
It appears McQueen has got himself a pit crew.
而且你看，他请了谁当总机械师
And look who he has for a crew chief！
啊，你们看，是韩森黄蜂！
Look，man。It's the Hudson Hornet！Whoa！
喔，我的老天爷，真的是他 麦坤真有一套
Well，dip me in axle grease and call me Slick！It surely is.
哇，这是历史上的大事
Wow，this is history in the making.
已经五十几年没有人见过这位赛车传奇了
Nobody has seen the racing legend in over 50 years！
嘿！韩大夫
Hey，Doc！
快来看“收音机”上这家伙 他跟你长得一样耶
Come look at this fellow on the radio。He looks just like you.
麦坤从内侧超过他们 可是他还落后将近一圈
McQueen passes on the inside！He's nearly a lap down.
只剩下60圈了，他能赶上吗？
Can he catch up to them with only 60 laps to go？
控制得很好，继续保持就行了
You're goin' great，kid。Just keep your head on.
嘿！小鬼！麦坤在哪找到你的？
Hey，shrimpie，where did McQueen find you，huh？
那些圆圆的东西叫轮胎 它们装在车子下面
Those round things are called tires，and they go under the car！
不要这样，奇诺！ 你会有机会的，你会有机会的
No！No，no！You'll have your chance。You will have your chance.
啊，小子想逞英雄，是吗？
Oh，kid's just tryin' to be a hero，huh？
试试这个
What do you think of this？
对，就是这样，小子
Yeah，that's it，kid.
什么？
What？
喔！帅呆喽！
Whoa！Git-R-done！
那是我教他的！咔嚓！
I taught him that。Ka-chow！Ah！
麦坤展现高超技巧，他追上领先者了
What a move by McQueen！He's caught up to the leaders.
好耶！现在是
Yeah。This is what it's all about.
名副其实的三强鼎立，角逐第一
A three-way battle for the lead，with ten to go！
那小子真不是盖的
Look at that boy go out there！
哼！你休想
No，you don't.
韩大夫，我暴胎了，我暴胎了！
Doc，I'm flat！I'm flat！
你能不能回到维修站？ 可以，应该可以
Can you get back to the pits？Yeah，yeah。I think so.
黄旗出现了，回来，小心别伤到底盘
Hey，got a yellow。Bring it in。Don't tear yourself up，kid.
我们得让他快点回跑道上
We gotta get him back out there fast
不然落后太多，就甭想拿到冠军了
or we're gonna be a lap down，and we'll never win this race！
奇诺，时候到了
Guido！It's time.
小鬼，你要洗他的挡风玻璃吗？
Hey，tiny，you gonna clean his windshield？
我真不敢相信！
I don't believe it！
我没见过这么快速的换胎
That was the fastest pit stop I've ever seen！
但是他得在前导车之前回到跑道上
It was a great stop，but he's still gotta beat that pace car！
会很接近
It's gonna be close.
耶！
Yeah，baby！
耶！他继续比赛喽！
He's back in！
做得好，奇诺
Guido，you did it！Way to go，Guido！
决胜时刻到了，现在进入最后一圈
This is it。We're heading into the final lap and McQueen
麦坤紧追在领先者后面，好一个败部复活
is right behind the leaders。What a comeback！
199圈，现在已经到了关键的最后一圈
A hundred and ninety-nine laps！It all comes down to this！
时候到了，小子
This is it，kiddo.
你剩下四个弯，一次一个
You've got four turns left。One at a time.
深入弯内，把持住
Drive it in deep and hope it sticks.
去
Go！
没那么容易
We'll see about that！
麦坤往内侧超车
McQueen's going inside！
路霸和冠军打滑了 我看麦坤要出局了
Chick and King are loose！I think McQueen's out！
麦坤救回来了 他回到跑道了
McQueen saved it！He's back on the track！
有凯迪拉克的优雅 有BMW的劲爆
Float like a Cadillac Sting like a Beemer！
闪电麦坤将拿下活塞杯
Lightning McQueen is gonna win the Piston Cup！
加油，你行的，你行的，贴纸王
Come on！You got it！You got it，Stickers！
我不要再输给你了，老头
I am not comin' in behind you again，old man.
哦，不！
Oh，no！
我赢了，宝贝！
I won，baby！Yeah！Oh，yeah！
他想做什么啊？韩大夫
What's he up to，Doc？
你在做什么啊？小子
What are you doin'，kid？
冠军应该跑完他最后一场赛车
I think The King should finish his last race.
你放弃了活塞奖杯，你知道吗？
You just gave up the Piston Cup，you know that？
我认识了一个怪老头 他让我知道了一件事
This grumpy old racecar I know once told me somethin'.
那只是个空杯子
It's just an empty cup.
达洛，最后一圈，在跑道上推车合法吗？
Darrell，is pushing on the last lap legal？
鲍勃，他不是在推他 他只是在帮助他加速
He's not really pushin' him。He's just givin' him a little bump draft.
嘿，怎么啦？发生什么事啦
Hey。What？What's goin' on？
那才是一流的赛车！
That's what I call racin'.
太棒了，我的朋友 做的好，小老弟
Bravo il mio amico！Way to go，buddy！
真是充满了爱耶！你知道吗？
There's a lotta love out there，you know，man？
别让我想吐，阿飞 他是我的偶像
Don't embarrass me，Fillmore。That's my hot rod.
快呀，宝贝，快拿出来 拿出活塞奖杯
Come on，baby，bring it out！Bring out the Piston Cup！
喀其卡！喀其卡！
Ka-chicka！Ka-chicka！
耶！就是这样没错
Yeah！Now，that's what I'm talkin' about！
嘿！为什么只有我一个在庆祝啊
Hey，how come the only one celebrating is me，huh？
小妞们呢？撒五彩碎纸啊
Where are the girls？Bring on the confetti！
轻一点！好吗？怎么回事啊？
Ow！Ow！Easy with the confetti。What's goin' on？
快，快拍照 我要跟戴诺可签约了！
Come on，snap some pictures。I gotta go sign my deal with Dinoco！
跟我说一遍，喀其卡！
Say it with me。Ka-chicka！
嘿！你们怎么了？噢！干吗生气啊？
What's wrong with everybody？Where's the happiness？
嘿！这是路霸时代的开始耶！
Hey！This is the start of the Chick era！
谢谢了，闪电 不客气
Thanks，Lightnin'。You're welcome.
冠军，你永远都是冠军
Way to go，King！You're still the car！
你是冠军！
You're The King！Yeah！
我们以你为荣！ 恭喜你输了，小子
You made us proud，kid！Congrats on the loss，me bucko！
你很有义气，小子
You got a lotta stuff，kid.
谢了，韩大夫
Thanks，Doc.
嘿，闪电
Hey，Lightnin'.
你过来跟我谈一谈，好吗？
How 'bout comin' over here and talk to me a minute？
孩子，你刚才表现得不俗
Son，that was some real racin' out there.
你想不想成为戴诺可的新代言人呢？
How'd you like to become the new face of Dinoco？
可是我输了
But I didn't win.
孩子，赛车并不只是为了赢而已
Lightnin'，there's a whole lot more to racin' than just winnin'.
他锈得太厉害了，当他走在街道上
He was so rusty，when he drove down the street
秃鹰会绕着他盘旋
buzzards used to circle the car！
谢谢你，老德，可是…
Thank you，Mr。Tex，but
可是当初是“清锈”汽车 给了我蹿起的机会
but these Rust-eze guys over there gave me my big break.
我要继续帮他们代言
I'm gonna stick with them.
好，那我就尊重你的决定
Well，I sure can respect that.
可是如果我
Still，you know，
能为你做任何事情，那就请你告诉我
if there's ever anything I can do for you，just let me know.
谢谢你的慷慨，谢谢你
I sure appreciate that。Thank you.
其实是有一件事
Actually，there is one thing.
嘿！你们！我在天上飞，我在飞！
Hey，look at me！I'm flyin'，by golly！
我比狂扫拖车公园的龙卷风还高兴
I'm happier than a tornado in a trailer park！
我觉得我们该重新装潢了
I think it's about-a time we redecorate.
你好！闪电麦坤告诉我 这里有全世界
Hi。Lightning McQueen told me this was the best place in the world
最好的轮胎
to get tires.
给我和我的朋友 各三、四组轮胎，好吗？
How 'bout setting me and my friends up with three or four sets each？
奇诺，有一辆真正的舒马赫法拉利在我店里
Guido！There is a real Michael Schumacher Ferrari in my store.
真的法拉利！
A real Ferrari！
打我，奇诺，打我的脸
Punch me，Guido。Punch me in the face.
这是我这辈子最光荣的一天
This is the most glorious day of my life.
希望你的朋友他没有事
Wow。Spero che il tuo amico si riprenda.
听说你们俩很厉害
Mi dicono che siete fantastici.
你是刚好路过吗？
Just passin' through？
其实是我想住一阵子
Actually，I thought I'd stop and stay awhile.
我听说这里又繁荣起来了 是吗？
I hear this place is back on the map。It is？
有传闻说，活塞杯的一辆知名赛车
There's some rumor floating around that some hotshot Piston Cup racecar
要在这个小镇成立他的赛车总部
is setting up his big racing headquarters here.
真的？我们的镇要沉沦喽
Really？Ah，well，there goes the town.
我真的很想你，莎莉
You know，I really missed you，Sally.
我带给别人的感受连他们自己都无法理解
Well，I create feelings in others they themselves don't understand and，
麦坤和莎莉躲在树底下
McQueen and Sally parked beneath the tree，
两部车子在…嗯…玩亲亲
Ki-s-s uh in-t！
真会挑时间啊，拖线
Great timing，Mater！
我走了，拜拜，拜拜
Hep-non，hip-hep，hi-li-lilly！Whee！
他是我最好的朋友，我能怎样？
He's my best friend。What're you gonna do？
赛一场吧，看我们谁先到芙蓉那里
So，Stickers，last one to Flo's buys？
换个花样，我们兜兜风吧
I don't know。Why don't we just take a drive？
嗯…不要
Hmm Nah.
耶！咔嚓！
Yeah！Ka-chow！
好了，请大家靠近一点
All right，everybody please keep together now.
我们现在来到的地方呢 是博物馆的韩大夫区
We is now entering the Doc Hudson wing of the museum.
哇！酷毙了！单季那么多次胜利
Wow。Unbelievable。That many wins in a single season.
他是真材实料，小子 韩森黄蜂是我的偶像
He's the real deal，Junior。The Hudson Hornet was my inspiration.
对不起，年轻人，韩大夫今天在吗？
Excuse me，son。Is Doc Hudson here today？
抱歉，冠军夫人，韩大夫他好像出去兜风了
Sorry，Mrs。The King，I think Doc went out for a drive or somethin'.
你真的不是沙地赛车的料
Well，you sure ain't no dirt boy.
你错了，老头 我知道你所有的诡计
Not today，old man。I know all your tricks.
韩大夫！韩大夫！
Doc！Doc！
不会让你看穿的，菜鸟！
Not all my tricks，rookie！
注意！立正！ 跟柏油路告别吧，男士们
Attention！Kiss the pavement goodbye.
等我训练完了，泥巴会出现在 你们意想不到的地方
When I'm finished，you'll have mud in places you didn't know you had！
不…我从没离开过马路 从现在起，这就要改变
Yo，I've never been off-road！Well，that's gonna change right now！
向后转！出去跑三十公里！
About face！Drop and give me 20 miles！
快快…快快快快快…快！
Go！Go！Go，go，go，go，go！Go！
哦…沙子跑进我的钢圈里了
Man，now I got dirt in my rims！
你看
Huh？Look at this！
是我的车盖！我的车盖！
It's my hood！It's my hood！
我有20年没有看见它了！
I ain't seen this thing in 20 years！
非常的合身，好不好看？
Well，it fits perfectly。How do I look？Ah-choo！
又没了
Oh，dang.
你只是玩具车！
You are a toy car！
你是可怜奇怪的小货车 我同情你，再见
You are a sad，strange little wagon and you have my pity。Farewell.
哦，是吗？一路顺风，你这个疯子
Oh，yeah？Well，good riddance，you loony！
我很不想打断房车拉力赛 可是，他们来了
Hey，I hate to break up the road rally，guys，but they're here！
庆生会客人在三点钟方向
Birthday guests at three o'clock！
天啊！谁配那小猪卡车的声音
Oh，man！Whoever does the voice of that piggy truck，
我告诉你，他是个好演员
I'm tellin' ya，he's one great actor！
我们被放逐了，天才 被困在这荒山野地，没有铁链
We're banished，genius！Stuck here in this wasteland without chains！
可是大眼仔，阿布汽车有麻烦 她需要我们帮助
But，Mike，the Boomobile's in trouble！She needs our help！
你根本没听我说话呀！
You're still not listening！Ah！
欢迎来到喜马拉雅山！甜筒？
Welcome to the Himalayas！Snow cone？
那个学人铲雪机真是喜剧泰斗
Oh，that Abominable Snowplow is quite the comic thespian！
快点进去！快快快！
Just get in there。Go！Go，go，go！
马戏团车？
Circus cars？
你们怎么会是马戏团车
How can you be circus cars？
这些是全世界最烂的马戏团车
These are the lousiest circus cars in the world，
他们会让我发大财
and they're gonna make me rich！
等一下！
Wait a minute here.
他们不断重复用同样的演员
They're just usin' the same actor over and over.
这是哪门子的小成本电影？
What kind of a cut-rate production is this？
哦，看在克莱斯勒份上 我们可不可以找辆车问一下路？
Oh，for the love of Chrysler，can we please ask someone for directions？
不行！快到匝道了！ 我知道！我感觉得到！
No！There's an on-ramp close！I know it！I can feel it！